百万美元宝贝
加油
Do it!
你能打败他! 你能打败他!
You got him! You got him!
我只遇见过一个我不想和他争斗的人
I only ever met one man I wouldn't wanna fight.
我止不了血
I can't stop that.
滚开吧 你个没有的东西
Get out of here, you useless tit.
我遇见他的时候 他已经是拳击界最好的伤口护理师
When I met him, he was already the best cut man in the business.
你能止住吗?
Can you stop it?
从60年代起就开始做训练师和经理人
Started training and managing in the '60s.
一直保持着高昂的热情
But he never lost his gift.
不行
No.
我来看看他
Let me have a look at him.
他没事 他没事
He's fine. He's fine.
如果你止不了血的话就不是没事
He ain't if you don't stop this bleeding.
我再给你一个回合
I'll give you one more round.
- 时间到了 来吧 - 我们怎么办?告诉我怎么办
- Seconds out. Let's go. - What do we do? Tell me what to do.
你让他打你
You let him hit you.
有时你就是无能为力
Sometimes there's just nothing you can do.
伤口太深 离骨头太近
Cut's too wide, too close to the bone.
也许是断了一条血管...
Maybe you got a severed vein...
或者你就是无法让止血药深入里面
...or you just can't get the coagulant deep enough.
- 加油! - 分开 分开
- Come on! - Break. Break.
在肌肉的不同层次
There are all kinds of combinations you come up against...
你会遇到各种不同的问题组合
...down in the different layers of meat...
而弗兰基全都知道如何解决
...and Frankie knew how to work every one.
- 对!加油! - 你在做什么?
- That's it! Come on! - What are you doing?
打倒他 威利!
Knock him out, Willie!
人们热爱暴力
People love violence.
他们会在车祸现场减慢车速查看死尸
They'll slow down at a car wreck to check for bodies.
就是这些人宣称他们热爱拳击
Same people claim to love boxing.
他们根本不了解拳击是什么
They got no idea what it is.
拳击是有关尊严
Boxing is about respect.
赢得你自己的...
Getting it for yourself...
同时剥夺对手的
...and taking it away from the other guy.
我先去发动车
I'll warm up the car.
邓先生?
Mr.Dunn?
我欠你钱?
I owe you money?
没有 先生
No, sir.
我认识你妈妈?
I know your mama?
这个我确实不知道 先生
Don't rightly know, sir.
- 那你想干什么? - 我参加了垫场赛
- Then what is it you want? - I was on the undercard.
而且我也赢了 我是麦琪·菲斯杰拉德
I won my fight too. Maggie Fitzgerald.
那么 麦琪·菲斯杰拉德 有什么事吗?
Well, Maggie Fitzgerald, what's up?
- 你有没有正好看了我的比赛? - 没有
- Did you happen to see it? - Nope.
我干的不错
I did pretty good.
我想你也许有兴趣训练我
Thought you might be interested in training me.
我不训练女孩子
I don't train girls.
也许你应该试试看 我打过的人都说我很凶狠
Maybe you should. People see me fight say I'm pretty tough.
小姐 光是凶狠并不够
Girlie, tough ain't enough.
这是个错误
It's a mistake.
车应该能向后退的 弗兰基
Car should be able to back up, Frankie.
帮我推一下 行不?
Just push, will you?
- 霍根有什么事? - 邀请我们参加头衔战
- What did Hogan want? - Offered us a title shot.
是时候了
About time.
我直接把他拒绝了
I turned him down flat.
再多打两三场比赛 你就准备充分了
Two or three more fights, you'll be ready.
好久以前就说是两三场比赛了 弗兰基
Been two or three more fights for a long time now, Frankie.
听着 威利 你只有一次机会赢得冠军
Look, Willie, you get one shot at the title.
输掉的话 可能就再没有机会了
You lose it, it may not come around again.
再多打两三场比赛 我们就准备充分了
Now, two or three more fights and we'll be ready.
都听你的 弗兰基
Whatever you say, Frankie.
弗兰基总喜欢说 拳击是一种不自然的运动
Frankie liked to say that boxing is an unnatural act...
因为拳击中的每样东西都是逆向的
...that everything in boxing is backwards.
有时...
Sometimes...
打出一记重拳的最好方法是退后一步
...best way to deliver a punch is step back.
我的主啊 请尽力...
Well, do your best, Lord...
保护凯蒂
...protect Katy.
还有安妮
Annie too.
至于其他的...
Other than that...
你知道我想要什么 所以我再重复也没有什么用
...you know what I want, there's no use me repeating myself.
但是退后太多 你就已经退出比赛了
But step back too far, you ain't fighting at all.
（圣马可教堂）
- 再见 - 再见
- Bye. - Bye.
神父 布道很精彩 让我流泪
Father, that was a great sermon. Made me weep.
你这周又有什么疑惑?
What's confusing you this week?
噢 就是那个老掉牙的三位一体的问题
Oh, it's the same old one- God- three- God thing.
弗兰基 大多数人幼儿园的时候
Frankie, most people figure out...
就知道一切都是信心的问题
...by kindergarten it's about faith.
是不是有点像三种不一样的萨其马
Is it sort of like Snap, Crackle...
都装在一个大盒子里?
...and Pop all rolled up in one big box?
你站在我的教堂外面把上帝比做点心?
You're standing outside my church comparing God to Rice Krispies?
你来做弥撒的唯一原因就是要骚扰我
The only reason you come to Mass is to wind me up.
- 不过今天不会了 - 我有点迷惑
- It won't happen this morning. - I'm confused.
- 不 你没有 - 不 我有
- No, you aren't. - Yes, I am.
那好 我给你的答案是 只有一位上帝
Then here's your answer: There's one God.
还有事吗? 我很忙
Anything else? Because I'm busy.
- 那么圣灵呢? - 他是上帝的爱的一种表现形式
- What about the Holy Ghost? - He's an expression of God's love.
- 耶稣呢? - 上帝之子 别在这儿装傻了
- And Jesus? - Son of God. Don't play stupid.
那么他是什么呢? 上帝的儿子意味着半神半人?
What is he then? Does that make him a demigod?
没有半神半人 操他妈的异教徒!
There are no demigods, you fucking pagan!
- 给你女儿写信了么? - 当然
- Did you write your daughter? - Absolutely.
你这是对一个神父撒谎
Now you're lying to a priest.
跟你说吧 休息一天 明天别来了
You know what? Take a day off, don't come to Mass tomorrow.
（斗场拳击馆）
有些人会说对于一个拳手来说
Some people would say the most...
最重要的莫过于热情
...important thing a fighter can have is heart.
弗兰基则会说 给我一个只有热情的拳手...
Frankie would say, "Show me a fighter who's nothing but heart...
我会告诉他什么叫鼻青脸肿
...and I'll show you a man waiting for a beating."
我想我只见过一个全心投入的拳手
Think I only ever met one fighter who was all heart.
我的名号是"战斗小子" 丹吉尔·迪拉德·巴奇...
My name's Dangerous Dillard Fighting Flippo Bam- Bam Barch...
来自德克萨斯布劳德县!
...out of Broward County, T exas!
丹吉尔是几年前来的
Danger showed up a couple of years back.
他和他妈妈的新男友艾瑞威尔 一起到洛杉矶来
He'd come visiting L.A. With Ervel, his mama's new boyfriend.
似乎艾瑞威尔迷了路 自己回德克萨斯
Apparently Ervel got lost and ended up back in Texas.
在来这里以前 丹吉尔找了他大概一个星期
Danger looked for him for about a week before he introduced himself.
你知道么 我对黑鬼从来没有任何偏见
Hey, you know, I gots nothing against niggers.
真高兴听你这么说
Well, that's nice to hear.
我的家乡很多人确实是那样...
Yeah, lots of people where I comes from does...
但是我妈妈告诉我不要伤害任何人...
...but my mama taught me not to cause hurt to no man...
不管是不是黑鬼
...niggers or not.
你妈妈还真是个好人 我可以帮你点什么嘛?
You got a nice mama. Anything else I can do for you?
你也许只是随便问个问题 ...
Just one of those questions you ask...
但是丹吉尔总想给你最好的答案
...but Danger wanted to give it his best answer.
我想成为次中量级世界冠军
Well, sir, I'd likes to become the welterweight champion of the world.
我要挑战"城市机动眼镜蛇"...
And I challenge the Motor City Cobra...
还有"刺客"汤马斯 赫尔斯...
...Thomas "Hit Man" Hearns...
争夺次中量级世界冠军!
...to fight me for the welterweight championship of the whole world!
冒失鬼 闭嘴 你连排名都没有
Yo, Flip, shut up, man! You ain't even ranked.
你最少要打一场比赛才能有排名
You gotta have at least one fight to be ranked.
我可以和任何人打 随时!
Hey, I'll fight any man, anytime!
你是个坏蛋 是吗?
Hey, you a bad man, huh?
进绳圈里来 我陪你玩一回合
Get in the ring. Go a round with me.
- 谢瑞尔 - 没问题
- Shawrelle. - I will.
别理他
Leave him alone.
丹吉尔 你继续训练
Danger, you go on back to training.
我会的 斯科雷普先生
Will do, Mr.Scrap.
你的紧身裤不错
Them's some nice tights, Danger.
我以后再揍你的屁股 小妞
I'll give you that ass- whupping later, Olive Oyl.
你的裤子还真不赖 丹吉尔
Hey, bro, those pants look real pretty on you.
把他妈妈的紧身衣还给她吧
Give his mama back her tights.
谢瑞尔·贝里的左钩拳可以打飞一辆坦克...
Shawrelle Berry had a left hook that would move a tank...
但是他的心胸却像豆子一样小
...but he had a heart the size of a split pea.
弗兰基17年前从巴比·马龙手里买下了斗场拳击馆
Frankie bought the Hit Pit from Bobby Malone 17 years ago.
巴比想搬到佛罗里达去 而弗兰基想要生活有点保障
Bobby wanted to move to Florida, and Frankie wanted some security.
巴比在他收拾行李的时候死掉了
Bobby died while he was packing.
弗兰基那时候才发现 大多数拳击馆都亏钱
And Frankie found out most gyms lose money.
我想我已经告诉过你 别让丹吉尔继续训练下去了
I thought I told you I didn't want Danger working out here anymore.
他又不会伤害到别人 弗兰基
He ain't hurting nothing, Frankie.
他伤害到我了
Well, he's hurting me.
我看着心疼 看他朝着空气挥拳
Breaking my heart, watching him punch the air...
好像空气会反击一样
...like he thinks it's gonna punch back.
还有我告诉你多少次了 漂白液就是漂白液
And how many times have I gotta tell you that bleach is bleach?
你就不能买便宜点的么?
Why can't you buy the cheap stuff?
不用买贵的那种
You don't have to buy the expensive stuff.
这种更好闻一些 弗兰基
It smells better, Frankie.
漂白液闻起来还是漂白液
Bleach smells like bleach.
- 斯科雷普 - 威利先生
- Hey, Scrap. - Hey, Mr.Willie.
昨晚打得不错
Hey, nice fight last night.
打得不错
Nice fight.
- 大个子威利 - 赛利
- Big Willie. - Hey, Sally.
- 打得不错 - 谢了 兄弟
- Nice fight. - Thanks, man.
有人在谈话
People are talking.
这他妈的是什么语言?
What the hell kind of language is that?
你想干吗?
What do you want?
我想你可能想知道 你有一个拳手...
I thought you might like to know you got a fighter out there...
不跟别的经理人说话
...not talking to another manager.
不跟别的经理人说话?
Not talking to another manager?
不是随便什么经理人
And not just any manager.
米奇·麦克
Mickey Mack.
你进来就是为了跟我说
You came in here to tell me that...
大个子威利不跟米奇·麦克说话
...Big Willie is not talking to Mickey Mack.
他们两个人一个字都没说
Not a word. Neither one of them.
我正打算读书
I'm trying to read here.
好吧 如果你觉得读书更重要
Well, if you think that's more important.
新来的那个女孩是谁?
Who's your new girl?
什么?
What?
我的老天
Jesus Christ.
最好快点
Better hurry up.
她要继续这么打沙袋 手腕迟早会断
She keeps hitting it like that, she gonna break her wrists.
你在浪费时间 我告诉过你我不训练女人
You're wasting your time. I told you I don't train girls.
我想你也许会改变主意
Thought you might change your mind.
外面有至少一打训练师训练女人 找到一个很容易
Dozens of trainers train girls. You won't have any trouble finding one.
我不需要一打 老板 您一个就会很好
Don't hardly need a dozen, boss. You'll do fine.
别叫我老板
Don't call me boss, now.
我不是你老板 你别再这么叫了
I'm not your boss, and don't you be calling me that.
- 威利 你准备好了么? - 随时可以开始
- Willie, you ready to work? - Anytime.
如果我不叫你老板 你会训练我么?
If I stop calling you boss, will you train me?
不会
No.
那我还是继续这样叫您好了
Then I might as well keep calling you it.
她从密苏里州西南部来...
She came from southwestern Missouri...
欧扎克地区的小城镇 西奥多西亚城外的山上...
...the hills outside the scratch- ass Ozark town of Theodosia...
一个雪松和橡树环绕 比偏僻更偏僻的地方
...set in the cedars and oak trees somewhere between nowhere and goodbye.
在成长的过程中她只知道一件事 自己是个垃圾
She grew up knowing one thing: She was trash.
是给我的狗的
It's for my dog.
尽管她可以跋涉1800英里 西奥多西亚还是就在那山上
She'd come 1800 miles, but Theodosia was still just over the hill.
我在打沙袋 老板
Working the bag, boss.
我不是你的老板 还有 是沙袋在打你
I'm not your boss. And that bag's working you.
把钱退给她
Give her her money back.
你确定?
You sure?
- 她付了多少钱? - 六个月的
- How much did she pay? - Six months.
- 我的老天 - 我去还给她
- Jesus Christ. - No, I'll give it back.
不 别装聪明了 好吗?
No, don't be a smartass now, will you?
这女人一定会觉得咱们为了赶她走...
Woman thinks I'll throw away six months' worth of dues...
连六个月的费用都不要 她肯定会发疯的
...just to get rid of her, she's out of her mind.
- 但是千万别鼓励她 明白了么? - 好
- But just don't encourage her, understand? - Okay.
丹吉尔在外面做什么? 他在看什么?
And what's Danger doing out there? What's he looking at?
好像是一瓶水
Looks like a bottle of water.
他付费了么?
He paid his dues?
费用? 他连裤子都买不起 你想让他付训练费?
Dues? Boy can't afford pants. Want him to pay dues?
出去吧
Get out of my office.
我操
Fuck me.
你不能把它当做沙袋
Can't think of it as a bag.
我虽然不是训练师
I'm not a trainer...
但是如果你愿意的话我可以示范一下
...but I can show you this if you'd like.
任何帮助我都会感激您
Appreciate any help I can get.
你要做的是 你要把它看成是一个人 明白吗?
What you wanna do is, you wanna think of it as a man, see?
他在不停地移动
And he's constantly moving.
冲着你 绕着你 远离你 明白吗?
He's moving towards you, around you, away from you. All right?
不要在他向你移动的时候击打他
Don't hit him when he's coming towards you...
因为他会把你向后推...
...because he's just gonna push you back...
化解你的击打让你失去平衡 对吗?
...he's gonna smother your punches and take your balance, right?
所以你要小心的注视他
So you watch him real carefully.
不停转动 这样你的头就一直在动
Keep rotating. That keeps your head moving.
一个肩膀放在后侧 这样你随时可以打出一记重拳
And keep one shoulder back so you're always ready to fire a power shot.
对吗?来 好 好 不停旋转 不停移动 好
Right? Go ahead, now. Good, good. Keep rotating, keep moving. That's it.
好 下巴收住
Good, good. Keep that chin tucked in.
继续 不停移动 不停移动
Come on around. Keep moving, keep moving.
- 好 好 好 - 像这样?
- Good, good, good. - Like that?
对 给它几下
Yeah. Give it a few shots.
下巴收住 下巴收住
Tuck that chin in, now. Tuck that chin in.
非常好 很好
Yeah, that's good. That's good.
等练完这个 我们就安排你打梨球
Now, you get this down, we'll put you on the speed bag.
你有梨球吧
You do have a speed bag.
我有钱买自己的之前先借用一下
I'll just borrow it till I can buy my own.
好 那你回家吧
All right, you go on home now.
- 我和你一起出去? - 不用 这里就是我家
- I'll walk out with you? - No, I am home.
- 想看看吗?
- Wanna see? - Yeah.
挺好的
It's nice.
我再打一会儿会不会打扰您?
Would it bother you if I worked a little longer?
不会 走的时候把门关好就行了
No, just pull the door closed when you leave.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果拳击运动中有诀窍的话...
If there's magic in boxing...
那么这种诀窍就是不停战斗 超越耐力的极限...
...it's the magic of fighting battles beyond endurance...
超越折断的肋骨 破裂的肾脏 和脱落的视网膜
...beyond cracked ribs, ruptured kidneys and detached retinas.
这种诀窍是 为了别人无法了解的梦想而赌上一切
It's the magic of risking everything for a dream that nobody sees but you.
好了 好了 伙计们 看好脚步
Okay, okay, fellas, watch the footwork.
对了 对了
Hey, that's it. That's it.
手举起来
Hands up.
刺 刺 刺
Jab, jab, jab.
冒失鬼
Hey, Flip.
冒失鬼 过来
Hey, Flippy, come here, man.
我想我找到一个你能打败的人
I think I found somebody you can beat.
我不和女人打
I don't fights women.
为什么不 兄弟? 太合适你了 你知道为什么吗?
Why not, bro? It's perfect, bro, because you know why?
因为她... 就像你 你可以和他打...
Because she... Like, you, you could fight to him...
然后可以亲亲他
...and then you could kiss to him.
然后你还可以再跟他打一次
Then you fight to him one more time.
听起来真美啊 哥们儿 像一首诗
That's beautiful, man. That's like poetry.
- 像一首诗 - 你他妈墨水不少啊
- It's like poetry. - You been reading and shit.
- 谢了兄弟 - 伙计 这是个女人?
- Thanks, bro. - That's a girl, man?
冒失鬼 我想你是对的
Flip, I think you right.
看看她的小奶子 就像蚊子咬的包
Look at her little bitty titties. They're like mosquito bites.
靠 含着一嘴不满 让我看看
Man, that's barely even a mouthful. Let me see.
我看了你上一场比赛 谢瑞尔
Saw your last fight, Shawrelle.
大多数时间脸都朝下 我还以为地板长了奶子呢
Spent so much time face down, I thought the canvas had titties.
地板长了奶子 看看我 我是谢瑞尔
Canvas has titties. Hey, look at me. I'm Shawrelle.
跟拳台做啊 跟地板做啊
Just humping the canvas. Humping the floor.
靠 兄弟 地板长了奶子? 挺搞笑的 兄弟
Come on, bro. The floor having titties? That's funny, bro.
闭嘴吧你 你们笑什么呢
Shut up, man. What you laughing at?
哥们儿 扶住沙袋 傻瓜
Man, hold the bag, stupid.
那边有奶子啊 哥们儿
Some titties right there, man.
冒失鬼 他们什么时候开始做男式紧身裤了?
Yo, when they start making those tights for men, Flippy?
废物
Punk.
好了 足够了 今天足够了
All right, that's enough. That's enough for the day.
- 我给你按摩一下 - 噢 我没时间 弗兰基
- I'll give you a rubdown. - Oh, I can't, Frankie.
孩子有钢琴课 我跟格蕾斯说我去送她
Middle one's got a piano lesson. I told Grace I'd drive her.
- 格蕾斯的车坏了? - 她讨厌那辆车
- Something wrong with Gracie's car? - She hates that car.
想把那辆旧车要回来 可是卖车的说他已经有买家了
Wants the old one back, but the dealer said he's already got a buyer.
我也许应该和卖车的谈谈
Maybe I should talk to the dealer.
那我真是感激不尽
I'd appreciate that.
好吧
Okay.
- 谢谢 - 回头见
- Thanks. - See you later.
那家伙按摩成瘾 今天他不想按摩
The man's a rubdown whore. Today he doesn't want one.
你在这里到底干不干活?
You ever do any work around here?
如果我是你的话 就不会操心我是不是干活
Not my job I'd worry about, if I was you.
小姑娘看起来有进步啊
Little girl seems to be coming along.
是啊 看起来好像甚至有人在训练她
Yeah. It's almost like someone's been helping her.
也许她就是天生的 看起来她还有两把刷子
She might just be a natural. Looks like she's got something.
她还有我的梨球 她有的就这么多
She's got my speed bag, that's what she's got.
我想知道她是怎么弄到的
I wonder how the hell she got that.
我也想知道
I wonder.
我想要拿回我的梨球
I'm gonna need that speed bag back.
- 这个? - 没错 它是我的
- This bag? - Yes, that bag. That's my bag.
如果你在这里打它 别人会认为我在训练你
And if you're hitting it, people will think I'm training you.
老板 这件事就这么糟糕么?
Is that such a bad thing, boss?
对 对 没错
Yes. Yes, it is.
你每碰一次这个球 我就损失一些生意
Every time you touch it, you're losing me business out here.
我得承认 我在这儿是丢人现眼
- I gotta agree, I am embarrassing myself. - Yeah.
你知道 我不能把这个随便借给别人
Well, I can't just lend it to anybody, you know.
我理解
I understand.
你看起来是个不错的女孩
Look, you seem like a nice girl.
- 我可以给你些建议么? - 感激不尽
- Can I give you some advice? - I'd appreciate that.
你可以在这里或者其他地方...
You'll find a trainer in this gym or somewhere else...
找到愿意训练女孩的训练师
...that's gonna wanna train a girl.
简直就像是马戏表演
It's the latest freak show out there.
问题是 他们只会浪费你的时间...
The trouble is, they're gonna be wasting your time...
因为你已经太老了
...because you're too old.
我不觉得我那么老了
I don't feel that old.
这个嘛 我也不觉得我老
Well, neither do I...
但是你看我还会和21岁的人打拳么?
...but you don't see me fighting 21- year- olds, do you?
训练一个拳击手要四年
Takes about four years to train a fighter.
你多大了?
How old are you?
- 在下个生日之前31岁 - 对呀 你看看
- Thirty- one until my next birthday. - Oh, well, there you go.
31岁了
Thirty- one.
你不会从31岁才开始练芭蕾舞 不是么?
You wouldn't start training to be a ballerina at 31, would you?
我已经练了大概三年了
Already been working it for three years.
那你连梨球都打不到? 你到底怎么训练的?
And you can't hit a speed bag? What kind of training is that?
从来没有人指导 老板
Never had any, boss.
我不想说 可是能看出来
Well, I hate to say it, but it shows.
但是必须有人跟你说实话
Somebody's gotta be honest with you.
我讨厌自己是那个说实话的人
I hate to be the one to tell you the truth.
对不起用了您的球 邓先生
Well, sorry for using your bag, Mr.Dunn.
- 你现在不会哭吧? - 不会 先生
- You're not gonna cry now, are you? - No, sir.
好吧
Yeah.
给
Here.
- 这个该死的东西你留着吧 - 不 你需要它
- Keep the goddamn thing. - No, you need it.
不 拿着吧
No, take the bag.
反正我都二十年没见过它了
I haven't seen it in 20 years anyway.
我还有三个 好好享受它 好吗?
I've had three since then. Just enjoy it, will you?
- 我只是在自己买之前暂时借用一下
- I'll just borrow it till I buy my own. - Yeah.
别丢了就行
Just don't lose it.
对 我知道 霍根...
Yeah, I know, Hogan...
你的拳手是冠军 所以我们不能对半分...
...your guy's the champ, so we don't split 50s...
但是如果我连四成...
...but if I don't see 40 percent...
听着 你同意六四开的时候再给我电话
Look, you call me back when it's 60- 40...
要不然就别打来了
...or don't call me back at all.
- 威利 - 弗兰基
- Hey, Willie. - Hey, Frankie.
出什么事情了么?
Something wrong?
对不起我就这么来找您
I'm sorry to come by your house like this.
我知道你不喜欢别人来串门
I know you don't like people dropping in.
你可不是外人 威利 什么时候来我都欢迎 进来吧
Oh, you're not people, Willie. You're welcome anytime. Come on in.
我是来谢谢您帮格蕾斯把车拿回来
I wanted to thank you for getting Gracie's car back.
你不用谢我
Oh, well, you don't have to thank me.
为自己的车多花1000美元 也不算帮什么忙
Paying an extra thousand dollars for your own car ain't exactly a favor.
格蕾斯看见那辆车的时候都哭了
Gracie cried when she saw it.
真的?
Really?
我还想跟您谈谈业务上的事情
I also needed to talk with you about business.
对了 我刚和霍根通了电话
Oh, yeah, well, I just got off the phone with Hogan.
我们连九月份的冠军赛都谈好了
We're all set for September.
除了分成的问题
Everything but the split.
我得离开你了 弗兰基
I gotta leave you, Frankie.
什么?
What?
威利 再打两场就到冠军赛了
Willie, the title's just two fights away.
不是这个问题 是...
It ain't that, it's...
就好像你说的 我只有一次机会
It's like you said, I got one shot.
如果我赢了
If I win.
我就可以在我还能挣的时候挣尽可能多的钱
I gotta make as much as I can while I can.
我需要有人能帮我实现
I need somebody in the action who can make things happen.
而且我得在比赛前换经理人
And I gotta make the change before the fight.
他说必须让他带我去打冠军赛 他才会签下我
Only way this guy say he'd take me is if he took me to the title.
所以我给你安排冠军赛 然后他带你去参加
So I get you the title fight, and this guy takes you there?
他说必须这样
Only way he'd do it.
很抱歉 弗兰基 我知道你等冠军很久了
I'm sorry, Frankie. I know how long you waiting on a title.
我也希望能和你一起
I wish it could've been with me.
米奇·麦克是个生意人 他什么也教不了你
Mickey Mack's a businessman. He can't teach you nothing.
你已经教会了一切我需要知道的
You already taught me everything I need to know.
有些话人们永远都不愿意听
There's some things people just don 't want to hear.
我要挑战"城市机动眼镜蛇"
And I challenge the Motor City Cobra
还有"刺客"汤马斯 赫尔斯...
Thomas "Hit Man" Hearns...
争夺次中量级世界冠军!
...to fight me for the welterweight championship of the whole world.
丹吉尔 我这个拳套不是白戴的
Danger, I'm wearing these mitts for a reason.
只是练习一下我的步伐 斯科雷普先生
Just working on my footwork, Mr.Scrap.
丹吉尔 你打一拳 要不然就滚出去
Danger, you throw a punch or get the hell out of this gym.
丹吉尔 好好想想那一拳 我马上就回来
Danger, while you thinking about that punch, I'll be right back.
我想我会狠狠打那一拳 斯科雷普先生
I'm thinking how I'm gonna hit it hard for you, Mr.Scrap.
没人忍心告诉丹吉尔 赫尔斯好多年前就已经退休了
No one had the heart to tell Danger that Hearns retired years ago.
威利的事情我听说了
I heard about Willie.
非常无情 太无情了
That's cold. That's dead cold.
当然 要不是你年纪都这么大了 还不算太残酷
Of course, it wouldn't be so bad if you weren't so damn old.
至少我还能用两只眼睛看
Yeah, well, at least I can see through both eyes.
不过也没给你带来多少好处 不是吗?
Didn't do you a lot of good though, did it?
我还有这个训练馆
Well, I've got the gym.
我这个年纪也不用再训练拳手了
Don't need to be training fighters at my age.
威利告诉你原因了?
Willie tell you why?
是米奇 米奇有他的关系
It was Mickey. Mickey's got the connections.
这不是因为关系 这是因为你对他没有信心
Oh, it ain't about connections. It's about you not believing in him.
我发掘了他 在他身上花了八年的心血
Well, I found him, I stuck with him for eight years.
这叫我对他没信心?
How's that for not believing in him?
两年前你就可以让他去打冠军赛了 他是知道的
You could've got him a title fight two years ago. Hell, he knew that.
他能在你身边呆这么久 我都感到吃惊
I'm amazed he stayed around this long.
这个嘛 去参加比赛
Well, getting there and...
和把腰带赢回家完全是两回事
...taking home the belt are two different things.
我应该怎么办 让他去参加赢不了的比赛?
What was I supposed to do, just put him in over his head?
不保护他?
Not protect him?
你是在保护他不让他拿冠军?
Oh, you were protecting him from the championship.
- 对 - 现在听起来合情合理了
- Yeah. - Well, now it makes sense.
那你又怎么样呢 斯科雷普?
Well, what about you, Scrap?
你的经理当时做了什么?
What did your manager do?
你曾经是多么优秀的拳手 比威利要棒
You were a hell of a fighter, better than Willie.
他给了你一场冠军赛 还是把你扔在那里...
He get you a title fight, or did he just bust you out...
让对手用拳头不停打你的头 直到把眼睛打没了?
...banging your head against other people's fists until you lost your eye?
至少我有个机会
I had my shot.
我去挥舞过我的拳头 没有人能说我没努力过
I went out swinging, and no man can say I didn't.
是啊 我记得
Yeah, well, I remember.
但是请不要因为
And excuse me if...
我不想让我的拳手下半辈子...
...I didn't want my fighter spending the second half of his life...
都在清扫别人吐在地上的口水而介意
...cleaning up other people's spit.
是啊
Yeah, right.
对 你是聪明人 你还学希腊语呢
Right, you're the smart one. You're the one learning Greek.
是高卢语
It's Gaelic.
你刚刚把自己参加 冠军争霸战的机会保护没了
Well, you just protected yourself out of a championship fight.
这句话用高卢语怎么说?
How do you say that in Gaelic?
抱歉
Sorry.
谢谢
Thanks.
冠军和大个子威利·琼斯 之间的较量继续进行...
The action continues as the champ is battling Big Willie Jones...
他被冠军用 连续的左右拳控制住了
...and commanding him with rights and lefts.
逼到了绳圈的边上 他在用左拳攻击...
Up against the ropes, he's hitting him with the left...
拳击是一种不自然的运动
Boxing is an unnatural act.
因为拳击中的每样东西都是逆向的
Because everything in it is backwards.
你想向左移动...
You wanna move to the left...
不是向左迈步 而是右脚趾用力
...you don't step left, you push on the right toe.
向右移动的时候左脚趾用力
To move right, you use your left toe.
你要迎着痛苦而上 而不是...
Instead of running from the pain, like a sane person would do...
像有理智的人那样躲避
...you step into it.
大个子威利反击了
But Big Willie comes back.
天哪 他一记右手拳击中了卫冕拳王
Oh, my God, he hits the champ with a right hand.
卫冕拳王倒下了
And the champ is down.
女士们先生们 裁判正在数点
Ladies and gentleman, the ref is in for the count.
大个子威利·琼斯 成为了新的世界冠军
And Big Willie Jones is the new champion of the world.
今晚发生的一切令人难以置信...
It's unbelievable how this has taken place tonight...
不过朋友们 新的冠军产生了
...but there you have it, folks, a new champion.
拳击中的每样东西都是逆向的
Everything in boxing is backwards.
要芝士汉堡吗?
Want a cheeseburger?
- 你给我买了个芝士汉堡?
- You bought me a cheeseburger? - Yeah.
我从没见你给别人买过芝士汉堡
I never see you buy anybody a cheeseburger.
我点了 可我吃不了 你愿意吃么?
Well, I couldn't eat it, and I ordered it. You want it?
我猜地球又开始转了
Well, I guess the planet can go back to spinning.
- 你看比赛了么? - 看了
- You watch the fight? - Yeah, I watched it.
威利打的不错
Willie did good.
这就是你要说的?
That's what you've got to say?
威利赢了 不是吗? 他打的不错
Well, he won, didn't he? He did good.
我看出你正在改变自己 学着敞开心扉 很不错
I see you been working on yourself, learning to open up. That's good work.
你看了?
You watch it?
是啊 我有HBO台
Yeah, I got HBO.
你怎么可能看得起HBO?
Now, how can you afford HBO?
我从什么时候起就叫你省钱了?
How long have I been telling you to save your money?
从我和"台风"路易斯 强森...
Ever since I fought Louis "Typhoon" Johnson...
在密西西比州图皮洛市的 俱乐部体育馆比赛以后
...at the Stadium Club in Tupelo, Mississippi.
- 真的? - 是的
- That true? - Yeah.
经理人跑路了 让我们自己搭车回家
Manager ran off and left you and me to hitch home.
你难道什么都不记得了么?
Don't you remember nothing?
我记得走到一半的时候 觉得自己要被私刑处死了
Well, I remember walking halfway and thinking I was gonna be lynched.
我记得你把口袋空空的我
I remember you leaving me with...
扔在那个加油站
...my dick in my hand behind that gas station.
是啊 我当时搭到一个便车
Yeah, well, I got a ride.
我一关上门那家伙就开走了
The guy took off before I hardly closed the door.
后来我不得不又往回走了两英里
I had to walk back two miles.
你的良心占了上风 这就是原因
Your conscience got the better of you, that's what.
那他妈是什么声音?
What the hell's that?
今天是她的生日
It's her birthday.
你的呼吸方法不对 这就是为什么你大口喘气
You're not breathing right. That's why you're panting.
今天是你生日 是吗?
So it's your birthday, huh?
那你多大了?
How old does that make you?
我32了 邓先生
I'm 32, Mr.Dunn.
我在这里庆祝 我又花了一年的时间洗盘子和当女招待
I'm celebrating that I spent another year scraping dishes and waitressing...
我从13岁就开始干这些了
...which is what I been doing since 13.
根据您的理论 我37岁之前打不出一记像样的拳...
And according to you, I'll be 37 before I can even throw a decent punch...
打了这个梨球一个月 一点进展也没有...
...which after working this speed bag for a month and getting nowhere...
我现在认识到 上帝的现实也许就是这样
...I now realize may be God's simple truth.
另外的现实是 我的哥哥在监狱里
Other truth is, my brother's in prison...
我的妹妹假装 自己的一个孩子还活着 诈骗福利金
...my sister cheats on welfare by pretending one of her kids is still alive...
我爸爸死了 我妈有312磅重
...my daddy's dead, and my mama weighs 312 pounds.
如果我还有理智的话 我应该回家去
If I was thinking straight, I'd go back home...
找个二手的活动房屋 买个炸锅 再来点夹心饼干
...find a used trailer, buy a deep fryer and some Oreos.
问题是 这是唯一我喜欢做的事情
The problem is, this is the only thing I ever felt good doing.
如果对于拳击来说我太老了 那我就一无所有
If I'm too old for this, then I got nothing.
这下你满意了吧?
That enough truth to suit you?
这是你的梨球?
This your speed bag?
把你的放在台子后面了 真希望能说那是我用坏的
Put yours behind the counter. Wish I could say I wore it out.
好了 停一下 停一下
Okay, just hold it. Hold it.
我要教你几件事情 然后给你找个训练师
I'll show you a few things, and then we'll get you a trainer.
不用了 抱歉
No, sorry.
- 你还打算讨价还价? - 是的 先生
- You're in a position to negotiate? - Yes, sir.
是的 因为我知道如果你正确的训练我
Because I know if you train me right.
我会成为冠军
I'm gonna be a champ.
我见过你看着我的样子
I seen you looking at me.
- 是的 用怜悯的眼神 - 你不要这么说
- Yeah, out of pity. - Don't you say that.
你不要这么说 如果不是事实的话
Don't you say that if it ain't true.
我要的是训练师
I want a trainer.
我不要施舍 我也不要帮忙
I don't want charity, and I don't want favors.
如果你不感兴趣 那我还要继续庆祝
If you're not interested, then I got more celebrating to do.
停 停 停
Stop, stop, stop.
该死 停下来 你到底在做什么?
Goddamn it, stop. What the hell are you doing?
好吧
Okay.
如果我来教你...
If I'm gonna take you on...
- 你一定不会后悔的 - 听我说就行了
- You won't never regret it. - Look, just listen to me.
- 如果我来教你... - 我保证我会非常努力
- If I take you on... - I promise I'll work so hard.
天 这已经是个错误了
God, this is a mistake already.
我听着呢 老板
I'm listening, boss.
如果我来教你 你一句话也不要说 你不能对我有疑问
If I take you on, you don't say anything, you don't question me.
不要问我问题 除了"是 弗兰基"以外什么也不要说
You don't ask why, you don't say anything except maybe, "Yes, Frankie."
还有我会试着忘记 你是个女孩这个事实
And I'm gonna try to forget the fact that you're a girl.
我就要求这么多
That's all I ask.
另外如果你受伤了别对我哭
And don't come crying to me if you get hurt.
- 好的 - 我们一言为定
- Alrighty. - We got a deal.
没 还没有
No, not quite.
我教你怎么打拳
I'm gonna teach you how to fight...
然后给你找个经理人 我就放手不管了
...then we'll get you a manager, and I'm off down the road.
- 我不想和你争 不过... - 别跟我争 我们就这么办
- I hate to argue with you, but... - Don't argue, that's the way we're doing it.
我会教你一切你需要知道的
I teach you all you need to know...
然后你自己去挣个一百万美元
...and you go off and make a million dollars.
我不管 被人打掉牙齿 我也不管
I don't care. You get your teeth knocked out, I don't care.
我不想听 这个东西就是这样
I don't wanna hear about it. That's just the way it's gonna be.
只有这样我才同意教你
It's the only way I'll do it.
好的
All right.
在训练场里我注意到一件事
Now, one of the things I've...
你从来不移动你的脚
...noticed around the gym is you never move your feet.
你总是呆呆的站在那里 你必须要移动你的脚
You stand there just flat- footed. You've gotta move your feet.
这是我将教会你最有用的东西之一
That's one of the best things I can teach you.
那么 你应该这么做
So here's what you do.
把自己...膝盖弯曲一点
You get yourself... Bend your knees a little bit.
摆好运动姿态 就好像你打算要打什么一样
Get in an athletic position. Look like you're gonna hit something.
- 怎么做 老板? - 就...打...梨球就行了
- Move them how, boss? - Just... Go... Hit the bag.
- 停 - 我做错什么了?
- Stop. - What'd I do wrong?
好 你做错了两件事情
Okay, you did two things wrong.
第一 你问了我一个问题 第二 你又问了一个问题
One is you asked a question, and two is you asked another question.
现在我要你做的 不是要打得多么狠
Now, what I want you to do, it's not about hitting it hard...
而是打得多么好 所以看着我
...it's how good you hit it. So watch me.
如果你愿意的话可以和我一起数
You can count with me if you want.
就是数数 数一的时候 我打一下球
It's just count. On a one- count, I hit right through the bag.
- 你能再示范一次么? - 数...
- Can you show me that again? - I just...
数一就行了 拜托
Just say "one," please.
- 一 - 好
- One. - Okay.
- 一 好 - 一
- One. Okay. - One.
对 就说一 很好 很好
Yeah, just say "one." That's good. That's good.
然后我移动到我的右脚
Then I move over to my right foot.
你可以看到我的重心都转移到右脚
You'll see my weight is shifting to my right foot.
然后我用我的手背攻击
Then I hit it with my back of my hand, sort...
就像用冰锥碎冰
...of like I'm chipping ice with an ice pick.
然后我转过来 转移到我的左脚
Then I come over, and I shift to my left foot...
然后用右手攻击
...and I hit it with my right hand.
还是冰锥的动作
And ice pick maneuver again.
再转到右脚上 再攻击右侧
And I come over on my right foot and hit it right.
就看着我的脚步
Don't watch anything but my feet.
就这么做 不停练习
Just do it like that. Just keep practicing.
你示范他们怎么站立 双脚和肩膀平行
You show them how to stand, keep their legs under their shoulders.
训练一名拳手 你必须在精神上把他们剥光
To make a fighter, you gotta strip them down to bare wood.
死了再休息
Rest when you're dead.
过来
Come here.
你不能只是 叫他们忘记以前知道的事情...
You can't just tell them to forget everything you know...
你要叫他们从骨子里忘记
...you gotta make them forget it in their bones.
让他们疲惫到只听你的话
Make them so tired they only listen to you.
只能听见你的声音
Only hear your voice.
只做你叫他们做的事情 不做其他事
Only do what you say, and nothing else.
脚步移动
Move your feet.
脚步移动起来 移动起来让我看
Move your feet around. Let's see you go.
教他们怎么保持平衡 怎么让对手失去平衡
Show them how to keep their balance and take it away from the other guy.
别这么低 看着我 右勾拳 然后向右
Not so low. Look at me. Right hook and just turn right.
如何用右脚趾产生动力
How to generate momentum off your right toe.
出刺拳时如何弯曲膝盖
And how to flex your knees when you fire a jab.
如何在后退中攻击
How to fight backing up...
好让对手在追击你时有所顾忌
...so that the other guy doesn't wanna come after you.
然后你要再全部教他们一遍
Then you gotta show them all over again.
一遍又一遍...
Over and over and over...
直到他们感觉一切与生俱来
...till they think they were born that way.
转移
Shift.
转移位置
Shift away.
好了 今天就到这里
Okay. That's enough for today.
不错 好姑娘
Good work. Good girl.
老板 你觉得我可以打比赛了么?
You think I ready for a fight, boss?
嘿 你过来
Hey. Hey, come here.
你都喘不过气了
You're not breathing.
不想和你争论
Hate to disagree with you.
你一有压力就喜欢屏住呼吸
Every time you get under pressure, you're holding your breath.
- 从现在开始别这么做 - 好的
- Now, stop doing that. - Okay.
除了这一点 我做得很好 是吧?
But other than that, I'm doing pretty good, right?
- 我是说 对于女孩来讲 - 我不训练女孩
- I mean, for a girl. - I don't train girls.
老板 你觉得我可以参加比赛了么
Think I might be ready for a fight, boss?
我们先找个经理人 然后我们再看看 好吗?
Well, we'll get a manager, and we'll find out, won't we?
我是想找一个 可是你一直让我抽不出时间来
I'd like to, but you been keeping me too busy.
- 有家人吗 老板? - 什么?
- Got any family, boss? - What?
我看你把所有的时间都花在我的身上了
You been spending all this time with me.
我不知道你有没有家人
I didn't know if you had any.
没有
No.
我是有个女儿 叫凯蒂
Well, I've got a daughter, Katy.
她就是家人啊
That's family.
但是我们并不那么亲近
We're not exactly close.
她多重?
How much she weigh?
什么?
What?
我的家庭问题和体重成正比
Trouble in my family comes by the pound.
是吗
Yeah.
不是很重
Not very big.
曾经很爱运动 不知道现在还有没有坚持
Used to be real athletic. Don't know if she kept it up.
那么 你怎么想?
So, what do you think?
我可以参加比赛了么?
I ready for a fight?
嘿 赛利
Hey, Sally.
过来一下 好吗?
Come here for a minute, will you?
弗兰基 能不能到后面来跟我谈谈?
Frankie, I need to see you in the back for a minute, okay?
- 我能和你说句话么? - 赛利是个很优秀的经理人
- Can I see you a minute? - Sally here's a real good manager.
他手下还有几个拿过金手套的选手 想要女孩吗 赛利?
Has a couple of Golden Glove boys. Looking for a girl, Sally?
如果有优秀人选的话
I'm looking for a good one.
看 这不就有了
Well, see, there you go.
很高兴和你合作 小姐
Nice working with you, girlie.
- 你有什么事? - 没什么 没什么
- What'd you want? - Nothing. It's nothing.
我没撒谎 我已经看过你训练了 你的左拳很厉害
I ain't lying, I've been watching you work. You got a hell of a left.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那你要不要试试? 看看是不是合适?
So you wanna give this a try? See if it's a fit?
- 噢 当然 - 好
- Yeah, sure. - Good.
好 因为我觉得你已经够资格比赛了
Because I think you're ready for a fight.
分开
Break.
我到底做错了什么 赛利? 每次我逼近都被她痛击
What am I doing wrong, Sally? Every time I get inside, she's on me.
你做得很好 你就快把她拖垮了 继续出拳
You're doing great. You're wearing her down. Keep punching.
- 我不好 我要输了 - 你就快把她拖垮了
- I ain't doing great, I'm losing. - You're wearing her down.
没事吧 亲爱的?看得清吗?
You okay, honey? Can you see okay?
- 加油 - 加油
- Come on. - Do it.
加油 加油!
Come on, let's do this!
没错!
That's it!
今晚真不错 不是吗?
Nice night, eh?
老天
Jesus Christ.
那姑娘是罗尼·华盛顿的拳手
That's Lonnie Washington's girl.
非常优秀的拳手
Hell of a fighter.
11场全胜
11- 0.
左拳 左拳举起来
Your left. Keep your left up.
罗尼旗下有很多优秀拳手
Lonnie's got a lot of good fighters.
轻量级冠军乔伊 阿达乔也在他旗下
He's got Joey Adagio, lightweight champ?
对
Yeah.
你的左拳 该死
Your left, damn it.
要是我肯定不会选她做第一个对手
Wouldn't have been my choice for her first fight...
不过赛利是个好经理人
...but Sally's a good manager.
- 他一定认为她能打败她 - 天哪
- He must think she can take her. - Jesus H.
左拳 左拳举起来
Your left. Keep your left up.
你认为这么远的地方她能听见?
You think she can hear you from back here?
当然 就算麦琪输了 对赛利也算不了什么
Of course, if Maggie loses, it wouldn't mean anything to Sally.
也许还对他有帮助
Might even help him.
让罗尼的女选手再胜一场...
Lonnie's girl gets another win...
罗尼也许会让赛利的轻量级拳手
...Lonnie might let Sally's lightweight...
去挑战乔伊·阿达乔的冠军
...fight Joey Adagio for the title.
赛利想要安排一场和阿达乔的比赛?
Sally's trying to set a fight with Adagio?
嘿 我知道什么?
Hey, what do I know?
我只是来欣赏比赛
I just come because I enjoy the fights.
上帝
Mother of God.
好了 分开
Okay, break.
嘿 过来 过来
Hey. Come here, come here.
嘿 过来
Hey. Get over here.
你老是放低左拳 别再放低左拳了
You're dropping your left hand. Quit dropping your left hand.
嘿 弗兰基 你能不能让我跟我的拳手谈谈?
Hey, Frankie, you mind if I talk to my fighter?
你干得还真不赖啊
You're doing a hell of a job.
你也是这样指导你的轻量级选手的?
Is this the way you advise your lightweight?
我是邓
Dunn.
- 你在干什么? - 我在说话 你在干什么?
- What are you doing? - I'm talking. What are you doing?
- 这是你的拳手么? - 是我的拳手
- Is this your fighter? - It's my fighter.
真的不是那么合适 赛利
It ain't fitting real well, Sally.
好吧 你来带她 反正她也屁都不会打
Fine, you take her. She can't fight worth a shit anyway.
谁告诉我到底怎么回事
Somebody tell me what's going on.
我迟到了 赛利刚才只是替我
I was late. Sally was just subbing for me.
你说她是你的拳手?
You telling me this is your fighter?
对 是我的拳手
Yeah, this is my fighter.
那么你有10秒的时间
Then you got 10 seconds.
我把左手举起来了
I keep holding my left up.
可当我出拳的时候 就总是会放下去
Then I throw a punch and it keeps dropping.
- 那就放下去好了 - 那就简单多了
- Well, let it drop. - That'd be a lot easier.
她认为她摸透你了
She thinks she knows you.
你左手每次放下 她就从上面打过来
Every time you drop it, she comes right over the top.
那你就等着她 明白吗? 她脑子里就这么多东西
So you just wait for her, see? That's all she's thinking about.
她收回右拳准备出击的时...你听见了吗?
When she cocks that right hand... You hear?
我听着呢 老板
I hear you, boss.
如果她那么做 你就向旁边躲一步
When she does, step to the side...
然后给她一记再见勾拳
...and come with a good- night hook.
- 能行吗? - 看我的吧
- Got one? - Got it right here.
- 好 - 开始吧 我等着呢
- Okay. - Fight, or I'm calling it.
去教训她吧
Go give it to her.
拳手的身体了解拳手自己所不了解的东西
The body knows what fighters don 't.
如何保护自己
How to protect itself.
脖子只能转动那么多
A neck can only twist so far.
哪怕再多转一毫米 身体就会说
Twist it just a hair more, and the body says:
嘿 还是让我来吧
"Hey, I'll take it from here...
因为很明显你不知道你自己在做什么
...because you obviously don't know what you're doing."
到中立区去
Neutral corner.
- 看见她怎么出拳了么? - 是的
- See the way she did that? - Yeah.
舒格 雷就会这么做 这女人好像他一样
Sugar Ray would do that. Girl's got sugar.
躺下 休息
"Lie down, now, rest...
等你恢复知觉我们再谈
...and we'll talk about this when you regain your senses."
这个叫做击倒心理
It's called the knockout mechanism.
现在放松一点 你干得不错
Don't get all carried away, now. You did good.
谢了 老板
Thanks, boss.
你...你忘了规矩
You... You forgot the rule.
- 告诉我规矩是什么? - 左手要抬起?
- Now, what is the rule? - Keep my left up?
规矩是要随时保护自己
It's to protect yourself at all times.
好 规矩是什么?
Now, what is the rule?
- 随时保护我自己 - 很好 很好
- Protect myself at all times. - Good, good.
你放弃了我 那对我是什么样的保护?
You gave me away. How was that protecting me?
那不是保护
It wasn't.
没关系了
It's okay.
- 我会练习我的左手的 老板 - 把水喝了
- I'll work on my left, boss. - Drink your water.
除了这一点 我怎么样?
Other than that, how'd I do?
很好 你做得很好
Fine. You did fine.
你还会再放弃我么?
You gonna leave me again?
永远不会
Never.
你工作的那个地方 有没有手工制柠檬酥皮派?
That place you work, do they have homemade lemon meringue pie there?
- 当然有 - 不是罐装馅料的那种垃圾
- Sure. - Not the kind with the canned- filling crap?
噢 是很大罐的那种 标签上写着"手工制作"
Oh, big can, yay size. Says "homemade" on the label.
- 我想你这个周末休息一下 - 这才星期四
- I want you to take the weekend off. - It's only Thursday.
- 你打算要和我争? - 我知道最好不要有这个想法 老板
- You gonna argue with me? - Know better than to do that, boss.
很好
Well, good.
某种角度来看 拳手大都很顽固
All fighters are pigheaded some way or other.
他们的某个部分总觉得
Some part of them always thinks...
在某件事情上自己比别人知道的更多
...they know better than you about something.
你能不能花几分钟讲讲圣母怀胎?
Can you spare a few minutes for the Immaculate Conception?
实际上 就算他们错了...
Truth is, even if they're wrong...
就算有那么件事情 可以把他们都毁了...
...even if that one thing is gonna be the ruin of them...
如果你能把他们彻底打败 那他们就不算是拳手了
...if you can beat that last bit out of them, then they ain 't fighters at all.
- 我记得我说过让你周一再来 - 没错 老板
- Thought I said I'd see you Monday. - You sure did, boss.
就是昨晚说的
That was last night.
你说不要和你争论
You said not to argue with you.
该死的女人总是不按我的指挥做事
Damn woman won't do a thing I tell her.
想听我的建议么?
You want my advice?
什么?
What?
你的鞋子哪去了?
Where are your shoes?
我给我的脚透透风
I'm airing out my feet.
你的袜子上净是大洞
You got big holes in your socks.
噢 没有那么大啦
Oh, they're not that big.
我不是给你钱去买新的了吗?
Didn't I give you money for some new ones?
这是我的睡袜
These are my sleeping socks.
我的脚晚上需要一些新鲜空气
My feet like a little air at night.
那你为什么要在白天穿它们?
How come you're wearing them in the daytime, then?
因为我白天穿的袜子上洞太多了
Because my daytime socks got too many holes in them.
那好 如果我多给你些钱 你能去买几双新的么?
Well, if I give you some more money, you buy some new socks.
拜托?
Please?
很有吸引力 不过我不能保证
Well, I'd be tempted, but I couldn't say for sure.
也许会跑到跑道上去
Might find its way to the track.
比赛结束 比赛结束
It's over. It's over.
麦琪没花多少时间就取得连胜
Didn't take Maggie long to hit her stride.
我解决了呼吸的问题
I got the breathing thing down.
不 你还是呼吸不正确
No, you ain't breathing...
因为你第一回合就把对方打倒了
...because you're knocking them out in the first round.
- 我还以为那就是重点 - 重点是让自己变强
- Thought that was the point. - The point is to get good.
把对方第一回合就击倒 自己怎么可能进步
Can't get good if you keep knocking them out first round.
我怎么给你再找到对手?
How am I gonna get you fights?
没人愿意自己的拳手被羞辱
Nobody wants to see their fighter embarrassed, now.
为什么我还要 打这种四回合比赛 老板?
Why am I still doing four- rounders, boss?
因为你的肺还打不了六回合
Because you haven't got the lungs for six rounds.
我一直这么在第一回合 就把她们击倒就行了
I do if I keep knocking them out in the first round.
弗兰基让她又打了场四回合比赛...
Frankie made her fight one more four- rounder...
只是让她明白谁说了算数
...just to let her know who was boss.
三 四 五...
Three, four, five...
六 七...
...six, seven...
抱歉 老板
Sorry, boss.
麦琪对此毫不怀疑
Maggie left no doubt about it.
好了 加油
All right, let's do it.
但是第一场六回合赛并没那么轻松
Her first six- rounder didn't go quite as smooth.
起来!
Get up!
到你的角落去
To your corner.
- 三 四 五... - 起来
- Three, four, five... - Get up.
- ...六 七... - 起来
...six, seven... - Get up.
- ...八 九 十 比赛结束 - 你能做到
...eight, nine, ten. It's over. - You can do this.
麦琪到了第一回合结尾才将对方击倒
Maggie didn't knock her out till the end of the first round.
在那以后 没有经理愿意 让自己的拳手和麦琪交手
After that, no manager wanted to put his fighter in with Maggie.
弗兰基不得不自己讨腰包 来给她安排比赛...
Frankie had to go into his pocket to get her decent fights...
靠给对方经理人贿赂 来增加对方参赛的兴趣
...sweetening the purse by paying managers on the side.
这并没能持续太久
That only worked for so long.
然后弗兰基做了他不愿意做的事
Then Frankie did something he hated doing.
他冒了次险
He took a chance.
开始
Box.
他把她晋升了一个级别
He moved her up in class.
这差点成为一个错误
That could've been a mistake.
注意右边!
Watch the right!
注意 注意
Watch it. Watch it.
分开 分开 后退 时间到
Break, break. Step back. Break. Time.
该死 该死 该死
Damn, damn, damn.
给我们两秒钟 好吗?
Give us two seconds, will you?
- 好 - 两秒钟就好
- Okay. - Just two seconds.
- 你的鼻梁骨断了 - 噢 该死
- Your nose is broke. - Oh, damn.
- 弄好它 - 我没办法 我没办法
- Fix it. - I can't, I can't.
- 你可以的 - 我不行 我准备弃权了
- You can fix it. - I can't. I've gotta call it.
我见你做过 弄好它
I've seen what you can do. Fix it.
我能把它按回去 但是我不能给你止血
I can snap it back into place, but I can't stop the bleeding.
医务裁判会中止比赛的
The ring doctor's gonna call it.
求你 弗兰基 你要是能帮我止血 我就能打倒她
Please, Frankie, if you can stop the blood, I can beat her.
咬住这个
Bite down on this.
- 吸气 - 什么?
- Inhale. - What?
- 吸气 - 什么
吸气
Breathe in.
- 可以? - 没问题
- Okay, huh? - Yeah, it's okay.
好 这个变成喷泉之前你有20秒钟...
All right, you got 20 seconds before this turns into a geyser...
血会喷到整个前排座位上的
...and it's gonna spray all over the front row.
你只有20秒
Twenty seconds, that's all you've got.
去吧
Now get going.
回到你的角落去
Go to your corner.
三 四 五...
Three, four, five...
- 加油 呼吸 呼吸 - ...六 七 八...
- Come on, breathe. Breathe. ...six, seven, eight...
九 十
...nine, ten.
"莫库什勒"
Mo cuishle.
- 好! - 太棒了!
- All right! - Yeah!
对
Right.
你在读什么
What you reading?
她说什么?
What's she saying?
想知道你在读什么
Wants to know what you're reading.
是叶芝的作品(爱尔兰著名诗人) 仰着点头
It's Yeats. Keep your head back.
你为什么不跟她说说叶芝呢?
Why don't you talk a little Yeats to her.
告诉她那是怎样一件乐事
Show her what a treat that is.
他妈的什么时候才能轮到她?
When the hell they gonna get to her?
我很好 弗兰基
I'm okay, Frankie.
- 你今天学到了什么? - 随时保护自己
- What'd you learn tonight? - Always protect myself.
- 规矩是什么? - 随时保护自己
- What's the rule? - Always protect myself.
- 麦琪·菲斯杰拉德? - 在这里
- Margaret Fitzgerald? - Here.
我就在这儿等你
I'll be right here.
- 你怎么样? - 我?
- How you doing? - Me?
- 对 你 - 我又没有受伤
- Yeah, you. - I'm not the one who's hurt.
鼻子断了并不是那么受伤
Broken nose don't hurt that much.
为什么你要告诉我这个?
Why are you telling me that?
没有原因
No reason.
可有些伤太深了 或是离骨头太近
But some wounds are too deep or too close to the bone.
不管你如何努力 都不能止血
And no matter how hard you work at it, you just can't stop the bleeding.
- 你给你女儿写信了么? - 每周都写
- Did you write your daughter? - Every week.
我真不明白你为什么要来教堂
I've no idea why you come to church.
在连续十二场比赛击倒对手胜出后
After her 12th straight knockout.
弗兰基得到几个非常不错的邀请
Frankie got a couple of real good offers.
第一个邀请是和 "兰熊"比丽·奥斯特曼...
The first was to fight Billie "The Blue Bear" Osterman...
争夺WBA次中量级头衔
...for the WBA welterweight title.
"兰熊"比丽
Billie "The Blue Bear."
比丽原来是东柏林的妓女
Billie was a former prostitute out of East Berlin.
她是这个级别里 手法最肮脏的拳手 臭名远扬
Had a reputation for being the dirtiest fighter in the ranks.
她看起来一点也不在乎...
Didn't seem to matter to her...
这样的动作可能会致人于死地
...that something like that could kill a person.
观众喜欢她
And the crowds loved her.
他没告诉她就把这场比赛拒绝了
He turned it down without even telling her.
下一个邀请是去挑战英国冠军
The next was to fight the British champ...
- 一个刚被比丽击败的牙买加女孩 - 喂?
- ...a Jamaican girl Billie just beat. - Hello?
不感兴趣
Not interested.
他也没接受那个邀请
He turned that down too.
可是很大一笔钱哪 老板
That's a lot of money, boss.
是啊 你挣钱了 为什么还在这里工作?
Yeah, you're making money. What are you still working here for?
那是冠军赛 对吧?
It's a title match, right?
你是英国人么? 那个冠军你拿不走的
Are you British? It's a title you can't take away.
她没什么好输的 你也没什么好赢的
She's got nothing to lose, you got nothing to win.
很可能仍然是一场不错的比赛呢
Might still be a good fight.
是啊 我刚把你升上次中量级
Yeah, I just... I just brought you up to welterweight.
能和跟你水平相当的选手打就不错了
Too good to fight these contenders.
还想他妈去挑战那些冠军?
You'd rather fight some bullshit champ?
我没发现有和我水平相当的选手啊
Didn't notice I was fighting any contenders.
如果你想的话 随时可以换经理
Well, you can get yourself another manager any time you want.
实际上 如果你有能力 把自己的脸保护得好一点的话...
In fact, if you'd learn to protect your face a little better...
我才不会拒绝这笔钱呢
...I wouldn't have to turn down this money.
我的脸暴露出那么多 可还没被击倒过 真是个奇迹
My face is out there so much it's a miracle I haven't been knocked out yet.
你今晚不要继续训练了
No, you can't work here anymore tonight.
我定了位子
I made us a reservation.
你去洗个澡吧
You might wanna shower.
你的
Here you go.
这是什么?
What's this?
你想要的东西 这不是什么秘密
Well, it ain't no big secret what you're wishing for.
把蜡烛吹了
Go on and blow.
谢谢你
Thank you.
33岁不算大的
Thirty- three ain't so old.
我39岁的时候还在参赛
I was still fighting at 39.
我打了23年
Fought for 23 years.
最近怎么样 斯科雷普
How's it going, Scrap?
不错 米奇
Doing good, Mickey.
不错
Doing good.
- 你要什么? - 咖啡
- What'll you have? - Coffee.
你们两个不讲话?
You two not speaking?
不太认识他
Don't hardly know him.
我在37岁生日之后遇到了弗兰基
I met Frankie right after my 37th birthday.
那时他干的工作是给拳手包扎伤口
He was picking up cut work.
我认为不可能的时候 他总能给我包扎好
He used to patch me up when I thought it was impossible.
有他在赛场边真不错
Good man to have in your corner.
是啊
Yes, he is.
我最后一次比赛 在圣伯蒂诺 他也陪了我全场
He stayed with me through my last fight in San Berdu.
我的经理喝醉了 不知所踪
My manager was off getting drunk somewhere...
只有我和弗兰基
...and it was just Frankie and me.
我被打得晕头转向
I was taking a hellacious beating.
每个人最多能参加多少比赛 都有个数字
Everybody's got a particular number of fights in him.
没人告诉你那个数字是多少
Nobody tells you what that number is.
我的是109场
Mine was 109.
我只是不愿承认
I just didn't want to admit it.
第四回合
Fourth round, this...
这里被打开了口子
...cut opens up.
鲜血涌进我的眼睛
Blood starts pouring into my eye.
他们本应该终止那场比赛的
They should've stopped the fight...
但是 妈的 我是个在圣伯蒂诺的黑人
...but, hell, I was a black man in San Berdu.
我到那里就是去流血的
Blood was what I was there for.
一回合接着一回合 我不断地让弗兰基给我包扎
Round after round, I kept getting Frankie to patch me up.
他想扔毛巾认输...
He's talking about throwing in the towel...
但他不是我的经理人 什么也不能扔
...but he ain't my manager, he can't throw in nothing.
一回合接着一回合...
Round after round...
他一直跟我争吵
...he's arguing with me.
我几乎是在笑他 因为 妈的 好像是打在他身上似的
And I'm almost laughing because, hell, it's getting more to him than to me.
我打了15回合
I go 15 rounds...
裁判判我输了
...Iose by decision.
第二天早上 我的眼睛没了
Next morning, I lose the eye.
23年来 他从来没说起过这件事
In 23 years, he's never said a thing about it.
没这个必要 每次他看我 我都能从他的脸上读出来
Doesn't have to. I can see it in his face every time he looks at me.
某种程度上
Somehow...
弗兰基认为自己应该终止那场比赛
...Frankie thinks he should've stopped that fight...
可以挽救我的眼睛
...should've saved my eye.
他一生都希望能收回那第109场比赛
Spends his life wishing he could take back that 109th fight.
但我却想参加第110场
I wanted to go to 110.
重点是
Thing is...
如果你想取得冠军
...if you wanna get to the title...
也许他并不是最好人选
...maybe he's not the one to take you there.
你告诉了麦克先生我们今晚会来这里?
You tell Mr.Mack we'd be here tonight?
继续吃你的蛋糕吧
You go on, eat your cupcake.
不用了 我来吧
No, I got it.
这就是规矩
It's the rule.
随时保护自己
Always protect yourself.
人们从不采纳自己的意见
People never take their own advice.
如果她要离开弗兰基 最好当时就做
If she was gonna leave Frankie, better she did it to him then.
米奇·麦克先生?
Mr.Mickey Mack?
麦琪·菲斯杰拉德
I'm Maggie Fitzgerald.
我听说你是非常好的经理人 给大个子威利做的很不错
I hear you're a real good manager, doing good things for Big Willie.
但我想你该知道 我是不会离开邓先生的
But I thought you should know I ain't never leaving Mr.Dunn...
所以你不需要再找借口好遇见我了
...so you don't need to make any more excuses to bump into me.
不好意思打搅你吃饭了
Sorry for interrupting your dinner.
麦琪总是喜欢刚一交手 就把对手击倒
Maggie always did like taking them out in the first round.
寄出的信总是原样退回
The letters always came back marked the same way:
上面写着"退还发件人"
"Return to sender."
我给你准备点咖啡
I'll make you some coffee.
你打算拿你的钱干些什么?
What are you doing with your money?
- 存起来 - 好孩子
- Saving it. - Good girl.
你知道 如果存够了就可以买座小房
You know, you save enough of it, you ought to get yourself a little house.
现金 不用贷款
Cash, no mortgage.
那还要存一段时间
Gonna be a while before I can do that.
是啊 可能还有一段时间...
Yeah, well, it might be a stretch...
但你得给自己弄个窝
...but you gotta get yourself a place of your own.
把钱浪费在无关紧要的东西上 你能得到什么?
Go around wasting it on things that don't matter and what do you got?
明白么?
You understand?
很快 如果你等得太久 你什么也得不到
Pretty soon, you wait long enough, you got nothing.
好吧 只要我存够钱
Okay, soon as I get the money.
我这一生中犯了很多错误
I made a lot of mistakes in my life.
我只是不想你走一样的路
I'm just trying to keep you from doing the same.
知道了 老板
I know, boss.
- 我不会长命百岁的 - 这是什么?
- I'm not gonna live forever. - What is it?
一盒关于你那个英国对手的录像带
It's a tape on that girl in England you're gonna fight.
如果你想去争夺冠军 我们得做...嘿!
If you're gonna go for the title, we got some moves to... Hey.
嘿 快他妈下来 知道我有多大岁数么?
Hey, get the hell down. You know how old I am?
- 谢谢老板 非常感谢
- Thank you, boss. Thank you so much. - Yeah.
不用谢 亲爱的 给 把...我把这个放到机器里去
You're welcome, darling. Here, just... Here, let me put this in the machine.
什么机器?
What machine?
你没有电视 是么?
Don't have a TV, huh?
没有
No.
耶!
Yeah!
好了 好的
All right. Okay.
- 还有十分钟 亲爱的 - 谢谢
- Ten minutes, love. - Thank you.
那家伙说他爱我
Man says he loves me.
他不可能是第一个这么说的男人
He's probably not the first one to say that.
除了我爸以外的第一个
First since my daddy.
我要是赢了 你说他会向我求婚么?
I win, you think he'll propose?
你赢了 我就向你求婚
You win, I'll propose.
看 我给你带了件礼物
Look, I got you a gift here.
我想这是其他人的吧
I think they gave you somebody else's.
不 不 就是这个
No, no, this is it.
"莫库什勒"是什么意思?
What's it mean?
不知道 是高卢语
I don't know. Just something in Gaelic.
- 真漂亮 - 我也这么认为
- It's beautiful. - Yeah, I thought so.
- 是啊 - 真丝的
- Yeah. - Real silk thread.
来自美国的挑战者...
From the United States of America, the challenger...
麦琪·菲斯杰拉德
...Maggie Fitzgerald.
"莫库什勒" 你看到她袍子上的字了吗?
Mo cuishle. Did you see what was on her robe?
- "莫库什勒" "莫库什勒" - "莫库什勒"
- Mo cuishle. Mo cuishle. - Mo cuishle.
她本不是本晚的卖点
She wasn 't the main attraction.
她的比赛是一场中量级拳王赛的垫场赛
She was on the undercard of a middleweight title fight.
但如果你问问在场的人...
But ask someone who was there...
他们都不记得 当晚参加比赛的其他选手了
...they couldn 't tell you who else fought that night.
开始
Box.
- 加油! - "莫库什勒"!
- Come on! - Mo cuishle!
"莫库什勒"!"莫库什勒"!"莫库什勒"!
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
"莫库什勒"!
Mo cuishle!
"莫库什勒"!"莫库什勒"!"莫库什勒"!
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
她很强
She's tough.
我无法靠近 我无法靠近打到她
I can't get inside. I can't get close enough to hit her.
- 你知道为什么吗? - 为什么?
- You know why that is? - Why?
因为她是个比你更好的拳手
She's a better fighter than you are.
她更年轻 更强壮 更有经验
She's younger, she's stronger, and she's more experienced. Now...
现在你打算怎么办?
...what are you gonna do about it?
去吧
Get in there.
开始
Box.
三 四 五 六..
Three, four, five, six...
七 八 九 十
...seven, eight, nine, ten.
"莫库什勒"!"莫库什勒"!"莫库什勒"!
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
- "莫库什勒"! - "莫库什勒"!
- Mo cuishle! - Mo cuishle!
你知道我可以问其他人 对吗?
I could ask someone, you know?
好啊
Good.
你知道以后告诉我
You find out, you let me know.
不管那个名字是什么意思 人们记住了
Whatever it meant, the name stuck.
麦琪打遍爱丁堡 巴黎 布鲁塞尔和阿姆斯特丹
Maggie fought in Edinburgh and Paris, Brussels and Amsterdam.
观众总是高呼"莫库什勒"
It was always mo cuishle.
看起来到处是爱尔兰人...
Seems there are Irish people everywhere...
或者是想成为爱尔兰人的人
...or people who wanna be.
当他们回到美国的时候...
By the time they came back to the States...
麦琪已经达到了一个新的水平
...Maggie was in a whole new league.
"莫库什勒"!"莫库什勒"!"莫库什勒"!
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
后来他们受到另一场冠军赛的邀请
After that they got another offer to fight for the title.
怎么分成?
What's the split?
- 六四开 - 好
- Sixty- forty. - Good.
好 我们六 你们四 因为麦琪是吸引观众的筹码
We'll take 60 and you take 40, being as that Maggie's the draw.
那个小女孩
That little girl?
你真的认为我说的不对? 你认为观众会说...
You think I'm wrong, really? You think people are saying...
他们想看一个破烂德国人
...that they wanna see some scabby Kraut...
痛揍无名氏小姐?
...beat up on little Miss What's- Her- Name?
你要能找到那样的人 我们就拿四
You find someone who says that, and we'll take the 40.
给你
There you go.
他们现在是六四开 不过最后会是五五开
They're at 60- 40, but they'll come up to 50- 50.
那女孩现在怎么样了?
How's that girl doing?
她脑震荡了 耳鼓膜破裂
Well, she's got a concussion and a broken eardrum.
她没事吧
She be all right?
- 她要是有事呢? - 也许我应该给她送点什么
- And if she isn't? - Maybe I should send her something.
你愿意的话 把你的奖金寄给她好了 我想她会接受
Well, you could send her your check if you'd like. I'm sure she'd take it.
老板?
Boss?
我们说起过的那座房子?
That little house we talked about?
我买下了
I bought it.
聪明的姑娘
Well, smart girl.
给我妈买的 离她现在住的地方不到一英里
For my mama. It's only about a mile from where she lives now.
如你所言 没有贷款
No mortgage, just like you said.
你是个好女儿
You're a good daughter.
她还不知道
She don't know about it yet.
我希望我们可以多待一天 开车到那里去
I was hoping maybe we could stay an extra day, drive over there?
我知道她想见你
I know she wants to meet you.
好吧 可以
Yeah, we could do that.
天哪 妈妈快出来
Oh, my God. Mama, come on out here.
麦琪回来了
Mary M's here.
- 这是约翰逊家的旧屋 - 不再是了
- This is the Johnsons' old house. - Not anymore.
它是你的了 妈妈 还有玛代尔和孩子们
It's all yours, Mama. For you and Mardell and the kids.
麦琪 这房子是你给我买的?
Mary M, you bought this for me?
对 是你的了 全部付清了
Yeah, all yours, free and clear.
亲爱的
Darling...
没冰箱 也没炉灶
There's no fridge. No stove neither.
在你们搬进来前 会准备好的
They'll be here before you move in.
- 你花了多少钱? - 你不用管
- How much money did this cost you? - Never mind that.
- 你不该这么做 - 您需要一个体面的住处
- You shouldn't have done this. - You need a decent place.
你不该这么做 你该先问问我的
You shouldn't have done it. You should've asked me first.
如果政府发现了 他们会停掉我的社会福利的
Government's gonna find out about this, they're gonna stop my welfare.
- 妈妈 他们不会的 - 他们会的 你很好 有自己的工作
- Mama, no, they ain't. - They are. You're fine, you're working...
但没有福利我活不下去
...but I can't live without my welfare.
妈妈我会给你寄钱的
Mama, I'll send you money.
医疗怎么办? 公费医疗会把我从名单上划掉
What about my medicine? Medicaid gonna cut me off.
- 我拿什么钱买药啊? - 我会给你寄更多的钱
- How am I supposed to get my medicine? - I'll send you more money.
我希望你没有预期JD要住进来
I hope you don't expect J.D. To move in with us.
你知道他快出狱了
He's getting out, you know.
为什么不把钱直接给我?
Why didn't you just give me the money?
为什么必须给我买房子?
Why'd you have to buy me a house?
不是必须 妈妈 但房子是你的了
I didn't have to, Mama, but it's yours.
如果想要钱 把它卖掉好了
You want the money, sell it.
我不...
I don't...
我知道你不想伤害我们...
I know you didn't mean nothing hurtful...
只是有时候你没把事情想清楚
...but sometimes you just don't think things through.
- 这倒是真的 妈妈 - 我会试着不把房子卖掉
- That's true, Mama. - I'll try and keep the house.
我只是担心养房子的那些费用
I'm just worried about all those expenses.
我会给你寄更多钱的
I'll send you some more money.
那个人把你打成这样的?
That man hitting you?
这是比赛留下的
It's from the fight.
我是一名拳击手 妈妈
I'm a fighter, Mama.
找个老公吧 麦琪
Find a man, Mary M.
过正常的生活
Live proper.
人们知道你的职业后就会嘲笑你
People hear about what you're doing and they laugh.
告诉你我很难过 但是他们嘲笑你
Hurts me to tell you, but they laugh at you.
嗨
Hi.
你养过狗么?
You ever own a dog?
没有
Nope.
我差点养了一只巴斯顿的中型狗
Closest I ever came was a middleweight from Barstow.
我爸养过一只德国牧羊犬 埃克斯
My daddy had a German shepherd, Axel.
埃克斯的后腿不太好
Axel's hindquarters were so bad...
它得用自己的前腿拖着自己
...he had to drag himself...
从一个房间走到另一个房间
...room to room by his front legs.
看他跑过厨房的地板
Me and Mardell would bust up laughing...
我和玛代尔都会忍不住大笑
...watching him scoot across the kitchen floor.
爸爸 他当时病的很重 自己都站不起来
Daddy, he was so sick by then, he couldn't hardly stand himself.
但一天早上他起床以后 把埃克斯抱到他的拖车上
But one morning he got up, carried Axel to his rig...
他们俩跑进树林里 又唱又叫
...and the two of them went off into the woods, singing and howling.
直到那天晚上他独自回来时
But it wasn't till he got home that night alone that I saw...
我才发现卡车里的铲子
...the shovel in the back of the truck.
好想再看看他们俩在一起的样子
Sure miss watching the two of them together.
我现在除了你谁都没有了 弗兰基
I got nobody but you, Frankie.
对 你还有我
Well, you've got me.
至少在你找到一个好经理人以前是这样
At least, that is, until we find you a good manager.
嘿 我们能在这停一下么?
Hey, can we stop just up here?
好
Yeah.
这里有附近最好的柠檬派
This place has the best lemon pie around.
没有那种恶心的罐装馅
None of that canned- filling crap.
现在我可以上天堂了
Now I can die and go to heaven.
我以前和爸爸常来这
I used to come here with Daddy.
我不知道像这样的地方会不会出售
Wonder if a place like this is for sale.
我还有点积蓄
I got a little bit of savings.
（艾记小吃店）
好 好 谢谢
That's fine, fine, thanks.
嘿 丹吉尔到底在看什么?
Hey, what the hell's Danger looking at?
好像是另外一瓶水
Looks like another bottle of water.
想和我们一起到拉斯维加斯去么?
Wanna come to Vegas with us?
看你们在老虎机那儿受罪?
Watch you suffer over the nickel slots?
我的心脏受不了那种刺激
My heart can't take that kind of pounding.
她有场冠军赛 对手是"兰熊"
Well, she's got a title shot. The Blue Bear.
百万美金对半分
Million dollars, split right down the center.
啊 不错啊 弗兰基 很不错
That's good, Frankie. That's real good.
我想找个好助手一起去
Well, I could use a good second.
但是找不到 所以我来问问你
Can't find one, I thought I'd ask you.
我他妈为什么会同意呢?
Now, why the hell would I wanna do that?
因为你是一个 从来没得过冠军的半瞎的老傻瓜
Well, because you're a half- blind old fool who never got there himself.
我想你可能想去体验一下 站在冠军赛的绳圈里的感觉
I thought you might like to feel what it's like to be in a ring on a title match.
不好意思 我替你遗憾了
Excuse me for feeling sorry for you.
我不去 你还是在拉斯维加斯找吧
No, you pick up somebody there in Vegas.
找个年轻点的
Somebody with young hands.
你不会哭吧? 我已经带上一个女孩了
You're not gonna cry now, are you? I've already got one girl.
如果我离开这地方一天...
I leave this place for one day...
知道回来时这里会变成什么样么?
...got any idea what it would look like when I come back?
和现在这样差不多吧
Kind of like it looks right now.
噢 去死吧
Oh, go to hell.
告诉麦琪没有拳王腰带不要回来
You tell Maggie don't come back here without a belt.
知道了
Will do.
嘿 斯科雷普先生
Hey, Mr.Scrap.
我有个问题 可是我觉得问出来好傻
I got a question, but I feel real stupid asking it.
在这里没有问题是愚蠢的 丹吉尔
No such thing as a stupid question there, Danger.
好吧
Okay.
你怎么把冰块从这么小的口里放进去的?
How'd you get all the ice in here through this little tiny hole?
我一直在想
I've been thinking on it.
但想不出来
Can't figure it out.
我来做给你看吧 丹吉尔
Why don't I show you, Danger.
- 你可以 你可以做给我看? - 我想可以 我想可以
- You could do that? You could show me? - I think so. I think so.
还有 斯科雷普先生 我有点觉得我准备好参加比赛了
Also, Mr.Scrap, I was kind of thinking I might be ready for a fight.
我拿了票 你准备好了么?
Well, I got the tickets. You ready?
- 我们坐飞机去? - 你宁愿开车?
- We're flying? - Would you rather drive?
你是问我吗?
You're asking me?
你是想坐飞机还是开车过去?
Would you rather fly, or would you rather drive?
我终于有权决定某些事了么?
So I finally get to decide something?
我说的就是这个意思
That's what I'm saying.
好吧
Fine.
好 飞过去 开车回来
Fly there, drive back.
这是我听过的最愚蠢的事 我们怎么会那么做?
That's the stupidest thing I've ever heard. How the hell we gonna do that?
你说过让我决定的
You said it was up to me.
丹吉尔 给他们点颜色
Give them hell there, Danger.
嘿 老家伙 马桶的水溢出来了
Hey, old school, the toilet's overflowing.
嘿 冒失鬼 过来一下
Hey, Flippy, come here for a minute.
我的天啊
Jesus.
老天爷
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
噢 上帝!
Oh, God!
蠢猪
Dumb- ass.
来呀 丹吉尔 来呀 丹吉尔
Come on, Danger. Come on, Danger.
来呀 防守
Come on. Defense!
本来我可以坐在海市蜃楼酒店里...
Could be sitting up at the Mirage...
喝着迈泰酒...
...drinking mai tais...
看着裸体女人
...Iooking at naked women.
来呀 丹吉尔 举起手来打呀
Come on, Danger, put up your hands and fight.
丹吉尔 出去吧!
Danger, get out of there!
反击啊 快点
Fight back! Come on!
- 对了 丹吉尔 对了! - 干得好 哥们儿
- There you go, Danger, there you go! - Good job, man.
左刺拳打他 来呀
Jab him with the left. Come on.
来呀
Come on.
嘿 来呀 冒失鬼
Hey, come on now, Flip.
- 你在干什么?放开他 - 好了 好了
- What you doing? Let him go. - All right. Okay.
我扶住你了 来 来
I got you. Come on, come on.
没事了
It's all right.
我们不需要教练
We don't need no corner trainer.
我怎么样 斯科雷普先生!
How'd I do, Mr.Scrap?
干得不错 丹吉尔 相当不错
You did good, Danger. You did real good.
你是我的英雄 棒极了
You my man. You rock.
冒失鬼 还没完呢
Come on, Flip, man, you ain't done.
你还没打出气势呢
You ain't even fight good yet.
每个人都可能输的
Anybody can lose one fight.
每个人都会输的 年轻人 你会东山再起的
Anybody can lose one, son. You'll come back from this.
你会是世界冠军的
You'll be champion of the world.
不 我不会的 斯科雷普先生
No, I won't, Mr.Scrap.
我早该知道的
I should have knowed.
- 快点 我们不需要闲扯 - 我来帮你
- Come on. We don't need to be talking. - Let me help you.
噢 不用 我可以 帮我把尼龙扣解开就行了
Oh, no, I can do her. Just untie the Velcro for me.
好了
All right.
喂 别摘手套啊 哥们儿 你还没用过呢 丹吉尔
Come on, don't take the gloves off, man. You ain't even used them, Danger.
能借用一下么 丹吉尔?
Mind if I borrow this, Danger?
小子 你是不是叫丹吉尔啊?
Man, I thought your name was Danger.
快起来
Come on, now.
我明白了 我要先打弱智 再打老头
Oh, oh, I see. Now I get to fight a retard and a old man.
给ESPN电视台打电话 因为这个东西可是不能言传啊
Call ESPN, because you can't write this shit.
当心 谢瑞尔 轻点 谢瑞尔
Look out, Shawrelle. Easy, Shawrelle.
继续 哥们儿
Keep going, man.
好了 兄弟
All right, man.
他也不那么厉害啊
He ain't so tough.
第110场
One hundred and ten.
去找个工作吧 废物
Get a job, punk.
赢了这场 我就告诉你是什么意思
Win this one, I'll tell you what it means.
我给你找了几个吹风笛的
I got you some pipers.
"莫库什勒"!"莫库什勒"!"莫库什勒"!
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
"莫库什勒"! "莫库什勒"! "莫库什勒"!
上啊
All right, now!
我要你不停击打她的胸部...
I want you to jab her right in the tits...
直到它们肿得掉下来为止
...until they turn blue and fall off.
女士们先生们 这一场是今晚的...
Ladies and gentlemen, this is the feature...
压轴节目
...presentation of the evening.
这一角是挑战者 麦琪·菲斯杰拉德...
In this corner, the challenger, Maggie Fitzgerald...
红角选手
...in the red corner.
在蓝角的是...
In the blue corner...
WBA次中量级世界冠军...
...the WBA welterweight champion of the world...
"蓝熊"比丽
...Billie "The Blue Bear."
上帝啊
Sweet Jesus.
菲斯杰拉德把蓝熊逼到绳圈的外围
Fitzgerald is pushing The Blue Bear around the ring.
她一上来的气势很猛
She's coming on strong.
挑战者快步移动 用组合拳向头部和躯干攻击
Challenger darts in, lands a combination to the head and the body.
- 一个右勾拳打中了冠军 - 好的
- And a right hook stuns the champ. - All right.
分开!
Break it up!
分开!分开!
Break it! Break it!
再这么干的话 就扣你一分 明白了吗?
Do that one more time, it'll cost you a point, do you hear me?
去打吧
Go fight.
你他妈的混蛋
You motherfucker.
靠 这他妈算什么?
Come on. What the fuck?
好了 不能再这样了 我要扣你一分
All right, that's it. I'm gonna take away a point.
蓝角选手扣一分
One point deduction off the blue corner.
反击了 打中了菲斯杰拉德...
- Comes back, hits Fitzgerald...
裁判 眼睛睁大点 你...
Ref, open your eyes, you...
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
冠军赛的第一回合结束了
The first round is in the books on this championship match.
- 拿住 - 好的
- Hold onto that. - There you go.
- 看起来不错 - 你再使那种阴招...
- Looking good. - You pull that crap one more time...
我就取消你的比赛资格
...you're disqualified.
没事的
It's gonna be all right.
毫不怀疑 老板
Got no doubt, boss.
好 照看好你自己
Okay, just watch yourself.
离这位夫人远点
Stay away from this dame.
去中立角 中立角
Go to the neutral corner. Neutral corner.
- 四 五 六... - 趴着吧 你个婊子
- Four, five, six... - Stay down, you bitch.
七 八 九
...seven, eight, nine.
好啊 好啊!
Yeah, yeah!
分开 分开
Break it! Break it!
菲斯杰拉德连续击打蓝熊
Fitzgerald continues to pummel The Blue Bear.
东德的冠军...
The East German champion...
好!加油!
Yes! Come on!
我来 我来!
I got it! I got it.
眼睛有点模糊 老板
Eyes are blurring, boss.
- 你需要几只眼完成比赛? - 一只足够了
- How many eyes you need to finish this? - One's enough.
- 好 - 那么...
- Good. - Now...
我怎么对付这只熊?
...what do I do about the Bear?
你知道绕到外侧 击打肝脏部位的套路吗?
Do you know that step into the outside and hook into the liver?
我一直都这么打的 可她是铜头铁臂
I been doing that. She's made of steel.
我不要你打肝脏的部位
I don't want you to go to the liver.
我要你照准 她的小屁股下面打 明白吗?
I want you to hit her right up under her skinny ass, understand?
照准坐骨神经打 不停的打那个部位
Right in the sciatic nerve. Just keep digging it in there.
而且要一直缠着她 你听到了么?
And just keep sticking her. You hear that?
- 裁判员怎么办? - 站在裁判和"熊"的中间...
- What about the ref? - Keep between the ref and the Bear...
就没问题了
...and everything will just be fine.
比赛是你的 提高警惕
This is yours. You keep your guard up.
保持注意力
You keep it up.
噢 好啊!
Oh, yeah!
分开 分开!
Break, break!
"莫库什勒"!"莫库什勒"!"莫库什勒"!
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
医生
Doctor.
来呀
Come on.
呼吸
Breathe.
很好 呼吸
That's it. Breathe.
很好
Good.
看着我 注意看我
Look at me. Concentrate on me.
呼吸
Breathe.
很好
Good.
就这样
That's it.
呼吸
Breathe.
亲爱的 感觉怎样?
How you feeling, darling?
留胡子啦 老板
Growing a beard, boss?
我想可能会增加我的女人缘
I thought it might help me with the ladies.
很难说哦
Can't say it does.
会不...会不会很疼?
Does it...? Does it hurt much?
一点也不
Don't hurt at all.
那很好
Well, that's good.
弗兰基呢?
Where's Frankie?
他在...
Well, he's...
他在外面和医生谈
He's out there talking to the doctors.
可能在教他们怎样做好本职工作
Probably telling them how to do their job.
他们在告诉他 我是C1和C2颈椎完全损伤
They're telling him I'm a C1 and C2 complete.
就是说我的脊椎断得很彻底 完全没法修复了
Means that my spinal cord's so broke they'll never be able to fix it.
我下半生都得这么躺着
Gonna be frozen like this the rest of my life.
我叫他们告诉他 我不知道他能不能接受的了
I asked them to tell him. I don't know how he's gonna take it.
你看了比赛么?
Did you see the fight?
当然
Of course I did.
你完全压倒了她 麦琪
You had her cold, Maggie.
我不应该把手放下去的
I shouldn't have dropped my hands.
我不该转身的
I shouldn't have turned.
随时保护我自己
Always protect myself.
这句话他和我说了多少遍了
How many times he tell me that?
是啊...
Yeah...
他说话总是喜欢一遍遍重复
...he does like to repeat himself.
你能告诉他我很抱歉吗?
Will you tell him I'm real sorry?
不能
No.
不 我不会这么做的 麦琪
I won't do no such thing, Maggie.
真是该死啊
Damnedest thing.
你有什么计划?
So, what's the plan?
我知道你已经计划好了 你还是告诉我的好
I know you got one, so you might as well tell me what it is.
是你的错
It's your fault.
对 她现在那样躺着 都是你的错
Yeah, it's your fault she's lying in there like that.
你缠着我让我训练她
You kept after me until I trained her.
我知道我不该这么做的 她再怎么说也是个女孩
I knew I shouldn't have done it, her being a girl and all.
其他的一切也不断向我显示 不要训练她
Everything kept telling me not to.
除了你
Everything but you.
我要把你从这儿弄出去
I'm gonna get you out of here.
这里的医生屁都不懂
These doctors around here don't know squat.
要不然他们为什么要在沙漠里住着?
Otherwise, why would they be living out here in the desert?
一旦你能被移动了...
As soon as you're able to be moved...
我会找个地方 有人真正学过医的地方
...we'll find some place where they've actually studied medicine.
你就在那里修养好了 我会...
You just rest there, I'II...
我正在办
I'm on it.
弗兰基肯定打遍了全美国医院的电话...
Frankie must have called every hospital in America...
寻找能告诉他 她可以被治好的人
...Iooking for somebody who'd tell him they could fix her.
有两次很接近成功 可他们给她做了彻底检查后...
He came close twice, till they checked her over...
也表示无能为力
...said there was nothing to be done.
两个月后 她病情稳定到可以被移动了
Took two months till she was stable enough to move.
他们有护士专门做这个 你知道的
They got nurses for that, you know.
可她们太业馀了
Yeah, but they're amateurs.
因为不能移动 她长了褥疮
She developed skin ulcers because she couldn't change positions.
谢谢你
Thank you.
他们坐着救护车 完成了六个小时的旅程
They made the six- hour trip by ambulance.
飞过去 开车回来
Fly there, drive back.
弗兰基找到的康复中心 是个不错的地方
The rehab center Frankie found was a nice place.
他们把麦琪照顾地很周到
They took good care of Maggie.
即使他们没有的话 她也不会抱怨什么
She wouldn 't have complained if they hadn 't.
每天要花几小时才能让她上轮椅
Took several hours every day to get her ready for the wheelchair.
一 二 三 起
One, two, three, up.
由于她无法自主呼吸
Since she couldn't breathe on her own...
呼吸器总是开着
...her respirators were always on.
氧气24小时不间断地 被输进她的身体里
Oxygen was pumped into her 24 hours a day.
麦琪的妈妈打电话来说 他们会来看她
Maggie's mama called to say they were all coming for a visit.
在接下来的两周里 她每天都在窗前等他们
She waited by the window every day for the next two weeks.
当然
Sure.
弗兰基最后终于追踪到了他们
Frankie finally tracked them down.
发现他们六天前就住进旅馆了
Learned they'd checked into their hotel six days earlier.
弗兰基一直给他们留言 但总没有回音
Kept leaving messages which were never returned.
你不用整天都待在这儿
You don't have to hang around all day.
我喜欢这里 没关系的
I like it here. I don't mind.
其实就算你不在 我也会来读书的
In fact, if you weren't here, I'd come here anyway to read my books.
妈妈马上会来分担一些负担的
Mama will be here soon to share some of the burden.
这不是什么负担
Well, it's no burden.
给
Here.
读读这个
Read this.
好了 好了 行了
Okay, okay, that's enough.
读得太糟糕了
That's terrible.
我给你翻成英文吧
Anyway, I'll tell you in English what you were saying.
上面说
It says:
"我要起身去了 去往那茵湖岛"
I will arise and go now And go to Innisfree
"用泥土和树枝 盖上一间小木房"
And a small cabin build there Of clay and wattles made
"我享受着彼方的宁静 它缓缓滴零"
And I shall have some peace there For peace comes dropping slow
"从晨曦的面纱 到蟋蟀歌唱的地方"
Dropping from the veils of the morning To where the cricket sings.
还不赖 对吧?
Not bad, huh?
你要盖一间小木屋么 老板?
You gonna build a cabin, boss?
- 我? - 对
- Me? - Yeah.
你知道 等你收山之后
You know, when you quit all this.
你是说拳击?
You mean boxing?
不 我永远不会收山的
No, I'll never quit.
我太喜欢那汗臭味道了 我想
I like the stink too much, I guess.
你想? 我看你边看书...
You think? Because I could see you there real easy...
边吃柠檬派很惬意呀
...with your books and lemon pie.
你呢? 想在小木屋里生活么?
How about you? Would you like to go live in a cabin?
我可以学怎么烤东西
I could learn how to bake.
那样的话 我...
Well, then, I'II...
我也许要开始找了
Maybe I'll start looking then.
是啊
Yeah.
- 去吧 - 好的 听起来不错
- Go ahead. - All right. Okay, sounds good.
嘿 我是弗兰基 邓 我们在密苏里见过
Hi, I'm Frankie Dunn. I met you back out in Missouri.
我女儿在哪?
Where's my little girl?
你们不应该回旅馆换身衣服再来吗?
Don't you think you ought to go back to the hotel and change?
她还不知道你们已经来了一周 忙着拜访米老鼠呢
She doesn't know you've been here a week visiting Woody and Mickey.
我们和我妹妹有正事谈
We got business with my sister.
你干吗不干脆告诉我们她在哪呢?
Why don't you just tell us where she is.
你肯定是JD 那你肯定是那个谈正经事的家伙?
Oh, you must be J.D. And you must be the business guy?
你们错过了一些东西
There's some rides you missed.
你们不如回去 我来告诉她你们来不成了
Why don't you go back. I'll tell her you couldn't make it.
我开了这么远的路来照顾孩子
I drove all the way here to take care of my child.
你却暗示我不是个好母亲?
And you're suggesting I'm not a good mother?
麦琪哪里都去不了
Mary M. Can't go nowhere.
否则我们早带她去逛迪斯尼乐园了
If we could've taken her to Disneyland, we would've.
麦琪·菲斯杰拉德?
Margaret Fitzgerald?
就在这里 301房间
Right down here, 301.
- 快来 妈妈 - 我们走
- Come on, Mama. - Let's go.
后来我看到自己呼吸
And I saw myself breathing.
我的身体上下起伏
Like, my body was going up and down.
我想 "为什么没人告诉我?"
I thought, "Why didn't somebody tell me?"
你的头发得洗了 有点太油了
Your hair needs washing. It's kind of greasy.
只是些...
It's just a...
只是些法律上的程序
It's just some kind of legal thing.
是什么?
What is it?
你们谈得怎样了?
How we all doing here?
不好意思 亲爱的 我们时间不多
Sorry, darling, but we ain't got a lot of time.
约翰逊先生收了我们一大笔钱
Mr.Johnson's charging us a lot of money to...
来保证这件事不出纰漏
...be here to make sure this is done proper.
你们不如把那个留下 我等会儿读给她听
Why don't you just leave that. I'll read it to her later.
嘿 老家伙
Hey, old man...
你是我们家人么?
...you part of our family?
别管闲事
Stay the hell out of this.
念给我听 妈妈
Read it to me, Mama.
只是些法律程序 用来保护你的钱的
Well, it's just something legal to protect your money.
妈妈你不用担心
Mama, you don't have to worry.
拳击协会会支付这里所有的费用的
The boxing commission's paying for all this, everything.
如果不呢 麦琪?
But what if they don't, Mary M?
约翰逊先生说他们可以收走我的房子
Mr.Johnson says they can take my house.
如果你把财产转移给你母亲 那就没人能动得了了
If you assign your assets to your mother, no one can touch them.
不用管医生 丧葬费什么的
No doctors, no funeral expenses.
- 什么都不用理会了 - 你看 不如你们把这个留下
- Nothing. - Yeah, look, why don't you just leave it.
我以后再读给她...
Then I'll just read it to her later on...
无意冒犯 这不关你的事
With respect, this ain't your business.
好吧 我在走廊里等
All right. I'll be out in the hall.
你一直是个好女儿 麦琪
You been a good daughter, Mary M.
你签了这份文件
You sign that paper...
就能照顾你一家
...it'll take care of your family...
正如你父亲所愿
...the way your daddy would've wanted you to.
你怎么签字呢?
How do you make your mark?
能拿住笔么?
Can you hold a pen?
她只能用牙齿 妈妈
She gotta do it with her teeth, Mama.
你得把笔放到她嘴里去
You gotta put it in her mouth.
好了 亲爱的
Here you go, honey.
你看了那场比赛么 妈妈?
Did you see the fight, Mama?
亲爱的 你知道我对那东西是什么感觉
Honey, you know how I feel about that.
我打得不错
I did pretty good.
你输了 麦琪
You lost, Mary M.
听说不是你的错 但你输了
Ain't your fault, the way I heard it, but you lost.
不能把你现在剩下的东西也输掉
Don't wanna lose the rest of what you got left.
对了
There you go.
你怎么了?
What happened to you?
这是什么意思?
Well, what's that supposed to mean?
妈妈 你带上玛代尔和JD回家吧
Mama, you take Mardell and J.D. And get home.
别等我告诉律师 你担心领不到社会福利...
Before I tell that lawyer that you were so worried about your welfare...
所以根本就没按规定 签那些房产的证明
...you never signed those house papers like you were supposed to.
所以只要我愿意 我可以把房子卖了...
So any time I feel like it, I can sell that house...
不用理你这个又肥又懒的乡巴佬
...from under your fat, lazy, hillbilly asses.
如果你敢再来 我就那么做
And if you ever come back, that's exactly what I'll do.
也许应该有人数点到10
Well, maybe someone ought to count to 10.
不是很好闻吧 医生?
Don't smell real pretty, does it, doc?
可能保不住了 麦琪
We might have to lose it, Maggie.
他们拿掉了我的腿 老板
They took my leg, boss.
不会有事的 听到吗?
It's gonna be all right, you hear?
我总能听到你的声音 老板
I always hear your voice, boss.
需要什么吗?
You need anything?
我想知道"莫库什勒"的意思
I need to know what "mo cuishle" means.
可是你没有赢啊
But you didn't win.
我不用告诉你的
I don't have to tell you.
你是我见过的最坏的人
You're the meanest man I ever met.
难怪没有人爱你
No wonder no one loves you.
你让我想起了我父亲
You remind me of my daddy.
他肯定是个...
Well, he must have been...
非常聪明 英俊的人
...a very intelligent, handsome man.
你不会再让我读叶芝了 对吧?
You ain't gonna make me talk no more Yeats, are you?
不 我...
No, I was...
正在看城市大学的宣传材料
...Iooking at this catalog from City College.
我想给你弄个轮椅...
I thought I'd get you a wheelchair...
可以用吸管控制的那种
...maybe the kind that operates by blowing through a straw.
我想你可能想去上学
I thought maybe you'd like to go back to school.
求你帮个忙 老板
I got a favor to ask you, boss.
没问题
Sure.
什么事都行
Anything you want.
记得我爸是怎么帮埃克斯的么?
Remember what my daddy did for Axel?
想都不要想
Don't even think about that.
我不能像现在这样 弗兰基
I can't be like this, Frankie.
在我已经成就那么多以后
Not after what I done.
我见识了整个世界
I seen the world.
人们高呼我的名字
People chanted my name.
喔...
Well...
不是我的本名 是你给我起的该死的名字
...not my name, some damn name you gave me.
可他们为我欢呼
But they were chanting for me.
我上过杂志
I was in magazines.
你以为我以前做过这样的梦么?
You think I ever dreamed that'd happen?
我生出来的时候只有2磅1.5盎司
I was born at 2 pounds, 1 and a half ounces.
爸爸以前总说我是打拼 到这个世界上的...
Daddy used to tell me I fought to get into this world...
我也会打出一片天地
...and I'd fight my way out.
那是我唯一想做的 弗兰基
That's all I wanna do, Frankie.
我只是不想为那个和你打
I just don't wanna fight you to do it.
我得到了我要的
I got what I needed.
全部都得到了
I got it all.
别让他们从我身边一点点地拿走
Don't let them keep taking it away from me.
别让我一直躺在这 直到听不见人们的欢呼声为止
Don't let me lie here till I can't hear those people chanting no more.
我不能
I can't.
求求你
Please.
拜托 不要求我
Please, don't ask me.
我在求呢
I'm asking.
我不能
I can't.
喂?
Hello?
午夜时分...
In the middle of the night...
麦琪自己找到了办法
...Maggie had found her own solution.
她咬舌了
She had bit her tongue.
停下来 停下来
Stop. Stop.
看着我 看着我
Look at me. Look at me.
差点失血过多而死 直到他们把她的伤口缝合
Nearly bled to death before they stitched her up.
在弗兰基到来以前
She came around and...
她恢复了知觉 把缝上的伤口又撕开了
...ripped them out before Frankie even got there.
他们又把伤口缝起来
They stitched her up again...
垫起了舌头 以免她再咬舌自尽
...padded the tongue so she couldn't bite.
你不能那么做 你知道的
You can't do it, you know that.
我知道 神父
I do, Father.
可你不知道她有多迟钝
But you don't know how thick she is...
训练她有多难
...how hard it was to train her.
其他拳手你叫他们做什么 他们就做什么
Other fighters would do exactly what you'd say to them...
但她却会问为什么这样 为什么那样
...and she'd ask, why this and why that...
然后还是按自己的方式去做
...and then do it her own way anyway.
她能去争夺冠军 我...
How she fought for the title, I...
不是靠任何...
It wasn't by anything...
不是靠听我的话
Well, it wasn't by listening to me.
但是她现在想死
But now she wants to die...
而我只想把她留在我身边
...and I just wanna keep her with me.
我向上帝起誓 神父
And I swear to God, Father, it's...
这样做是犯罪
It's committing a sin by doing it.
让她活下去 实际上是在杀死她
By keeping her alive, I'm killing her.
你明白我的意思么? 我怎么才能克服呢?
Do you know what I mean? How do I get around that?
你不需要 你不要插手 弗兰基
You don't. You step aside, Frankie.
把她交托给上帝
You leave her with God.
她没有求上帝帮忙 她求我帮忙
She's not asking for God's help. She's asking for mine.
23年了 我基本上每天 都能在弥撒上见到你 弗兰基
Frankie, I've seen you at Mass almost every day for 23 years.
只有那些为了某些事 而不能原谅自己的人
The only person comes to church that much...
才会这么频繁地来教堂
...is the kind who can't forgive himself for something.
无论你身上背负着什么罪
Whatever sins you're carrying...
都无法和这个相提并论
...they're nothing compared to this.
忘记上帝 天堂和地狱吧
Forget about God or heaven and hell.
如果你那么做 你会迷失的
If you do this thing, you'll be lost.
深深地迷失
Somewhere so deep...
深到再也找不回自我了
...you'll never find yourself again.
我想我已经是了
I think I did it already.
我们一直给她镇静剂 好保证她不会再那么做
We're keeping her sedated so she won't try that again.
我今早去看了麦琪
I went to see Maggie this morning.
你一定是去了其他地方
You must have been somewhere else.
是啊
Yeah.
你在和一个我不认识的对手奋战?
You got a fight I don't know about?
那不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
我当时那么说是错误的
I was wrong to say that.
你说得真对
You're damn right.
我给你找到一个拳手
I found you a fighter...
你让她发挥出了最大的潜力
...and you made her the best fighter she could be.
我杀了她
I killed her.
别那么说
Don't say that.
麦琪走进那扇门的时候 除了胆量什么都没有
Maggie walked through that door with nothing but guts.
根本没有机会实现她的梦想
No chance in the world of being what she needed to be.
一年半以后 她在争夺世界冠军
A year and a half later, she's fighting for the championship of the world.
是你的功劳
You did that.
每天都有人死去的 弗兰基
People die every day, Frankie.
拖地的时候 刷碗的时候
Mopping floors, washing dishes.
你知道他们最后一个念头是什么吗?
And you know what their last thought is?
"我从没有过机会"
"I never got my shot."
因为有你 麦琪得到了属于她的机会
Because of you, Maggie got her shot.
如果她今天就死去 你知道她最后一个念头是什么吗?
If she dies today, you know what her last thought will be?
"我觉得我干得不错"
"I think I did all right."
我会觉得心安理得的
I know I could rest with that.
是啊
Yeah.
我去冲杯咖啡
I'm gonna get a cup of coffee.
好
Yeah.
好了
All right.
我会拔掉你的呼吸器...
I'm gonna disconnect your air machine...
然后你就会睡着
...then you're gonna go to sleep.
然后我给你打一针 你就...
Then I'll give you a shot, and you'II...
会一直睡下去
...stay asleep.
"莫库什勒"...
Mo cuishle...
的意思是"我的挚爱 我的血肉"
...means "my darling, my blood."
他只给她打了一针
He gave her a single shot.
肾上腺素的剂量是需要量的好几倍
It was enough adrenaline to do the job a few times over.
他不想让她再受一次苦
He didn't want her going through this again.
然后他走出门去
Then he walked out.
我想他什么都没有了
I don't think he had anything left.
我回到拳击馆
I went back to the gym.
等待着 认为他总有一天会回来
Waited, figuring he'd turn up sooner or later.
就在那时一个鬼魂走进门来
And that's when a ghost came through the door.
我想过你说的话了 斯科雷普先生
I got to thinking what you said, Mr.Scrap.
结果呢 丹吉尔?
What was that, Danger?
每个人都会失败的
Anybody can lose one fight.
这是实话
That's the truth.
去吧 戴上手套 你已经很长时间没训练了
Go on, put your gloves on. You missed a lot of training.
好的 斯科雷普先生 没问题
Will do, Mr.Scrap. Sure thing.
弗兰基再也没回来
Frankie never came back at all.
（凶狠是不够的）
弗兰基没留下讯息 没人知道他去了哪
Frankie didn't leave a note, and nobody knew where he went.
我希望他是去找你了
I'd hoped he'd gone to find you...
去再次请求你的原谅
...and ask you one more time to forgive him.
但也许他心中什么都没有了
But maybe he didn't have anything left in his heart.
我只希望他能找到个地方 享受片刻的安宁
I just hope he found someplace where he could find a little peace.
一个雪松和橡树环绕
A place set in the cedars and oak trees.
比偏僻更偏僻的地方
Somewhere between nowhere and goodbye.
但那可能只是一厢情愿
But that's probably wishful thinking.
无论他在哪儿
No matter where he is...
我想你该知道你父亲 究竟是个什么样的人
...I thought you should know what kind of man your father really was.